What you doing there?
Working on a new plan
to catch the roadrunner? Heh, heh.
The humorous implication
being that I am Wile E. Coyote?
Yes.
And this is a schematic
for a bird-trapping device...
...that will ultimately backfire
and cause me physical injury?
Yes.
[FAKES LAUGH]
Okay, what I'm doing here is trying
to determine when I'm going to die.
Mm-hm. A lot of people
are working on that research.
So, what is all this?
My family history factoring in longevity,
propensity for disease, et cetera.
Interesting.
Cause of death for Uncle Carl
was KBB?
- What's KBB?
- Killed by badger.
How's that?
It was Thanksgiving.
Uncle Carl said, "I think there's a badger
living in our chimney.
Hand me that flashlight."
Those were the last words
he ever spoke to us.
I don't think you need to worry
about death by badgers being hereditary.
Not true.
The fight or flight instinct
is coded genetically.
Instead of fleeing,
he chose to fight barehanded...
...against a brawny member
of the weasel family.
Who's to say
that I don't share that flawed DNA?
Hmm, we can always get a badger
and find out.
[FAKES LAUGH]
But seriously, even if I disregard
the Uncle Carl factor...
...at best, I have 60 years left.
That long, huh?
Sixty only takes me to here.
I need to get to here.
What's there?
The earliest estimate
of the singularity.
When man will be able to transfer
his consciousness into machines...
...and achieve immortality.
So you're upset about missing out...
...on becoming some sort
of freakish self-aware robot?
By this much.
Tough break. You want eggs?
You don't get it, Leonard.
I'm going to miss so much.
Unified field theory,
cold fusion, the dogapus.
What's a dogapus?
The hybrid dog and octopus.
Man's underwater best friend.
- Is somebody working on that?
- I was going to.
I planned on giving it to myself
on my 300th birthday.
Wait, you hate dogs.
A dogapus
can play fetch with eight balls.
No one can hate that.
What do we owe you?
It came to 28.17.
Let's say six bucks a piece.
Here you go.
Thank you.
- What?
- Uh...
- Never mind. I got it.
- Oh, you wanted me to pay.
- It's no big deal.
- Right.
We're not going out anymore,
I should pay for myself.
[BOTH GIGGLE]
What?
He said if he had woman parts,
he'd eat for free the rest of his life.
Yeah, but you wouldn't be able
to talk to yourself.
[LEONARD LAUGHING]
I'm a little low on cash.
- How much you got?
- Nothing.
- How can you walk around with no money?
- I'm cute, I get by.
It's okay, you can owe me.
Sheldon, six bucks.
Oh, no, thank you.
I'm not eating pizza tonight.
But it's Thursday.
Thursday's pizza night.
SHELDON:
Not for me.
Thursday is now
cruciferous vegetable night.
Tonight's selection, Brussels sprouts.
Really? You're changing
the Sheldonian calendar?
It's a small price to pay.
- For what?
- No, don't ask.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
To live long enough to fuse
my consciousness with cybernetics...
...I need to change my diet.
- Wait, cybernetics is robot stuff, right?
- Correct.
You wanna turn yourself
into some sort of robot?
Essentially, yes.
Okay, here's my question:
Didn't you already do that?
LEONARD:
Heh, heh, heh.
Flattering, but sadly, no.
I'm also planning
to begin an exercise regimen...
...designed to strengthen my
cardiovascular system, a.k.a., jogging.
Wait, honey,
have you ever run before?
Certainly. I've run from bullies,
dogs, angry chickens...
...and one particularly persistent
PE teacher...
...determined to bend me over
and give me a scoliosis test.
[WHISPERS INAUDIBLY]
You're right. Penny jogs.
- Maybe you guys can run together.
- That's an excellent idea.
Yeah, if we chat...
...it will create the illusion
of time going faster.
No, it won't.
Um, hey, how does he know I jog?
Oh, he watches you from his car
with high-powered binoculars.
Oh, my God, that is so creepy.
I know.
[WHISPERS INAUDIBLY]
And he says he's not gonna stop.
Yeah, well, then see a shrink
and figure out how to talk to women.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[SHELDON GROANS]
[SHELDON GROANING]
What the hell?
What's the matter?
I have pain radiating from my navel
to my lower right abdomen.
I'm nauseated and feverish.
I believe I may have cholera.
There's no cholera in Pasadena.
Just like last summer
when there was no malaria in Pasadena.
Well, if it's not cholera,
then based on a quick Internet search...
...the other explanations
in decreasing order of likelihood...
...are Hirschsprung's disease,
botulism, a 30-foot tapeworm...
...or accidental ingestion
of chrysanthemum blossoms.
When would you have accidentally eaten
chrysanthemum blossoms?
It's part of an unlikely scenario
that involves sleepwalking...
...in a 24-hour flower mart
with a less than vigilant proprietor.
Oh, Lord, my belly.
Ever had your appendix out?
I haven't. I've been meaning to,
but who has the time?
Let's get you to the hospital.
So this is how it ends.
[GROANING]
With cruel irony.
Just as I make the commitment
to preserving my body...
...I am betrayed by my appendix,
a vestigial organ.
Do you know the original purpose
of the appendix, Leonard?
- No.
- I do.
And yet I'm doomed while you live on.
Funny how things work out, isn't it?
SHELDON:
Oh, Lord, I think it's about to burst.
[SHELDON FARTS]
On the other hand,
it might have been the Brussels sprouts.
- Good night.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Appendicitis. What a nervous Nelly.
Penny. Penny. Penny.
PENNY:
Coming, coming.
Hey, nice knees.
- Thank you. They're my mother's.
- Oh.
And the Flash shirt is what?
Because you're gonna run fast?
No.
The Flash shirt is because it's Friday.
But it's nice when things work out.
- Heart rate monitor?
- Don't have one.
- Your pedometer?
- Telematics connected to an iPod?
- Uh, nope.
What do you do?
You just go out there
and gambol about like a bunny?
No, I just run till I'm hungry
and then I stop for a bear claw.
- Why are you doing that?
- It's good to stretch before you run.
All right.
Let's start with a toe touch.
Okay, you do it.
I am doing it.
Oh, wow. Good job.
Okay, um, can you do this?
We'll never know.
Okay, let's just, uh, warm up on the run.
- Okay.
- Okay, let's go.
Yeah,
I've been reading up on biomechanics.
I think you'll be surprised at my...
[SHELDON & PENNY SCREAMING]
[THUMPING WHILE FALLING]
PENNY: Oh, my God, are you okay?
SHELDON: I think so.
PENNY: Oh, let me help you up.
SHELDON: Thank you.
[SHELDON FARTS]
PENNY:
Oh, Sheldon.
SHELDON:
If it makes you feel any better...
...Thursday is no longer
cruciferous vegetable night.
Here's my chicken curry.
- Howard, your shrimp biryani.
- Thank you, sir.
- Palak paneer, that's Penny.
- Thanks.
And for Rajesh Koothrappali...
...from whose homeland
these originate...
...one large order
of Chicken McNuggets.
- Hey, what's my share?
- Uh, twelve bucks.
- Can I get you after Friday?
- Sure.
What am I up to now?
Well, okay, uh,
with the Indian food, the pizza...
...the Thai food, the tank of gas,
the frozen yogurt and your rent...
...uh...
...a little over $1400.
[BOTH GIGGLE]
- What now?
- He's just expressing his admiration.
You don't even have to put out
to get free stuff.
[BOTH GIGGLING]
It's not free. I'm gonna pay him back.
[BOTH GIGGLE]
Shut up!
Sheldon, are you gonna join us?
SHELDON:
Coming.
Greetings, friends.
Greetings, whatever the hell you are.
I am a mobile virtual presence device.
Recent events
have demonstrated to me...
...that my body is too fragile
to endure the vicissitudes of the world.
Until such time as I am able
to transfer my consciousness...
...I shall remain in a secure location
and interact with the world...
...in this manner.
[WHISPERS INAUDIBLY]
Really? That's your question?
When did he put a ramp in?
You're in my spot.
This may seem a little odd at first...
...but over time,
you'll grow accustomed...
...to dealing with me
in this configuration.
Yeah, to be honest,
I don't see much difference.
Thank you.
That's what I was going for.
Now, Leonard,
tomorrow when we go to work...
...you'll need to allow some extra time
to get me down the stairs.
For your convenience,
I disassemble into four pieces.
This is ridiculous.
I'm coming to talk to you.
You don't know where I am.
My physical body
is safely ensconced...
...in a secure, undisclosed location.
You're in your bedroom.
No, I'm not.
I can hear your voice
coming from your bedroom.
No, you can't.
Wait. Come back.
Halt.
Authorized personnel only.
So either one of you weirdoes wanna
buy my underwear? Only 1400 bucks.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Sheldon, this is ridiculous.
I'm behind you.
Please look at me
when you're talking to me.
I am looking at you.
No, you're not.
Pay no attention to that man in the bed.
You cannot exist
as a virtual presence.
Not here and certainly not at work.
Oh, good God.
At my age, do you know
how I'm statistically most likely to die?
At the hands of your roommate?
An accident.
Well,
that's how I'm gonna make it look.
Until I can transfer my intellect
to a more durable container...
...my body will remain safely ensconced
in my bed.
Fine, but don't expect my help.
You have to help.
It's in the roommate agreement.
No, it's not.
Section 74-C.
The various obligations and duties
of the parties...
...in the event
one of them becomes a robot.
I'll be damned.
- This is delightful.
- Uh-huh.
It's much easier to enjoy
the picturesque route we travel to work...
...when you remove the specter
of fiery vehicular death.
Refresh my memory.
Why didn't I just put you in the trunk?
Because I called shotgun, remember?
Right.
You seem tense.
Perhaps this will relax you.
[FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING ON SCREEN]
I don't wanna listen to music,
Sheldon.
[FLUTE MUSIC STOPS]
Very well.
I don't understand
why you're not enjoying this.
Together in this car
with my enhanced capabilities...
...we're like Knight Rider.
Except in Knight Rider,
the car isn't a yammering sphincter.
You mock the sphincter,
but the sphincter is a class of muscle...
...without which human beings
couldn't survive.
There are over 50 different sphincters
in the human body.
How many can you name?
I was wrong.
This is exactly like Knight Rider.
Perhaps you'd be interested
in a different game.
No.
This is a photograph
of the 1911 Solvay Conference...
...on the theory
of radiation and quanta.
Using Photoshop,
I've introduced a few anachronisms.
See if you can spot all 24.
I'll give you the first one.
Madame Curie should not be wearing
a digital watch.
And go.
[FLUTE PLAYING "JEOPARDY THEME"
ON SCREEN]
That's it. Bye-bye.
[FLUTE MUSIC STOPS]
Bazinga!
[TIRES SCREECH
AND HORN HONKING]
I have an override switch.
I almost died.
Yeah, and I'm safe and sound in bed.
Who's crazy now?
I'm still gonna go with you.
Hello, Professor Hoskins.
Nice to see you, Mindy.
Konnichiwa, Dr. Nakamora.
Sorry, the Swedes
disproved your theory.
Leonard, my door.
What about it?
Be a lamb and open it for me.
Why? What's the problem?
You think you have me stymied,
don't you?
No, I think a doorknob
has you stymied.
Oh, look, it's Leonard and R2-D-Bag.
[LAUGHS]
That's my joke, I told it last night.
You can't just use it.
Raj, be a lamb
and open the door for me.
Oh, sure.
He's a lamb, you're not.
I'm a lamb.
Isn't this nice?
The pleasures of fellowship
and camaraderie...
...without having to tolerate
your germy breath on my skin.
I say we just take him to Tatooine
and sell him to some Jawas, heh.
That's two, dude.
Write your own jokes.
[SIGHS]
Oh, great.
- Hi, I'm Penny. I'll be your waitress.
- Why are you introducing yourself?
I'd rather people not know I have any
prior connection to you whatsoever.
Can you tell me the specials
this evening?
- Sheldon, I'm not waiting on you.
- Obviously.
I don't even have water yet.
Because you're not here.
That's discrimination
against the otherwise located.
I'm going to have to go
over your head.
Manager?
Oh, Lord, look who it is.
- Is that Steve Wozniak?
- I think it is.
The great and powerful Woz.
Penny, Steve Wozniak was one
of the co-founders of Apple computer.
He and Steve Jobs...
Yeah, I know who he is.
I watch Dancing With the Stars.
I must speak to him.
Of course you must.
There's an Olive Garden down the street.
You guys should try it sometime.
Excuse me, Mr. Wozniak?
Oh, hey. Nice virtual presence device.
Thank you.
I just wanna say I'm a big fan.
You're my 15th favorite
technological visionary.
Only 15th?
It's still six spots above Steve Jobs.
I care neither for turtlenecks
nor showmanship.
Yeah,
I never got that turtleneck thing.
One of my proudest possessions
is a vintage 1977 Apple II.
Despite the file system limitations
of Apple DOS 3.3...
...it was a pretty nifty
little achievement.
Thanks, we were shooting for nifty.
You know, if you had it here,
I'd autograph it for you.
Don't move for 15 to 30 minutes...
...depending on how the busses
are running.
Nerds.
[SHELDON PANTING]
SHELDON:
I'm coming, Woz. I'm coming.
Ah!
[THUMPING WHILE FALLING]
[COMPUTER CRASHES]
Aw.
SHELDON:
Penny.
What up, Shel-Bot?
I can't get out of bed. I hurt my ankle.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Sing me "Soft Kitty."
Really? You want me to sing "Soft Kitty"
to a computer monitor?
Would you rather come
sing it to me in person?
[SINGING]
Soft kitty, warm kitty
Little ball of fur
Closer to the microphone.
Happy kitty, sleepy...
No.
You have to start over.
Softy kitty, warm kitty
[PLAYING FLUTE]
Little ball of fur
Happy kitty, sleepy kitty
Purr, purr, purr
[English - US - SDH]