Sheldon, your food's getting cold.
I'll eat later. Right now I'm suckling at the
informative bosom of mother physics.
It's hot when Sheldon talks dirty.
So I found this website
where you send them pictures...
...they sculpt your head
and make an action figure out of you.
- How awesome is that?
- Let me see.
You can pick your wardrobe,
you can choose your accessories.
Oh, Leonard,
you can get a little asthma inhaler.
Oh, this is neat.
Think about all the action figures
we've bought.
It would be kind of cool
to have one that look like us.
Yeah, if that's your idea of what's cool,
you should get one.
Yeah, so I'm out.
What do you think?
Want an action figure that looks like you?
- Would it come with kung-fu grip?
- No.
Don't waste my time.
You get that these
are personalized action figures.
Honey, if you want one, just get one.
- You're still out, right?
- Yup.
A hush falls over the crowd
as Cooper studies the board.
He makes his move.
He's dividing both sides by I,
he's adding back the coefficient.
He has a value for P.
He's plugging that back in.
He takes the derivative
and he solves the equation.
- Crowd goes wild. "Nobel, Nobel!"
- Cooper.
"Nobel." Kripke.
Yeah... Don't look at my board.
- What's that?
- That's a drawing of a really cool train.
Yeah, don't look at that, either.
- What do you want?
- I have some bad news.
You're working on a grant proposal
for a new fusion reactor.
I'm working on a grant proposal
The university is only allowed
to submit one proposal.
So they asked you to pack up your things
and ship out. That's hard cheese, Barry.
You're one of the good ones.
No, they're making us work together.
That's ridiculous.
I am one of the great minds
of our generation.
I work on a level so rarified,
you couldn't even imagine it.
I said, stop looking at my cool train!
Hm. A strange place to put a picture
of you and Bernadette.
Well, I've wanted everybody
to know I love my wife, you know...
...and nobody to know
I forgot to turn off the laser.
They're here.
Our action figures have arrived.
It's the best $500 I've ever spent.
A thousand dollars on action figures?
How can you afford that?
Easy. His family is loaded
and Bernadette has a great job.
My wife came with both funbags
and moneybags.
Say hello to an exact-scale model of me.
Oh, I'm not dark chocolate.
I'm melt-in-your-mouth caramel.
Oh, man.
Look at my nose.
Maybe it's a shipping problem.
- What?
- Yeah.
Maybe Wesley Snipes and Toucan Sam
just got action figures and look like you. Heh.
- This sucks.
- I can't believe I wasted all that money.
Aw, and my girlfriend
wouldn't let me get one.
Look at my face.
Do I look smug? I feel smug.
I hate it when you make me sit
through the credits.
Well, sometimes there's a secret ending,
like in The Avengers.
Yeah, but I don't think that's gonna
happen in a documentary about the Holocaust.
They could show bloopers.
- Oh, no.
- What is that?
That is Sheldon's "I'm unhappy
and about to destroy the planet" music.
- Let's just go to your place.
- Lf he's unhappy, shouldn't we talk to him?
"Shouldn't we talk to him?"
Have you learned nothing in six years?
You doing okay, sweetie?
There's ominous music playing
and there's an afghan over my head.
I don't know where you're from, but where
I'm from, that means I'm not doing okay.
- I'm gonna make you some tea.
- Tea is for when I'm upset. I'm not upset.
The university is forcing me
to work with Kripke. I'm outraged.
So cocoa?
Yes, cocoa.
Do you have any idea what it's like
to be paired with someone so annoying?
Oh, teacher, me, me.
You see, I did all this great work
and now he's just gonna come and ruin it.
I'm angrier than ever
and filled with despair.
- What beverage do you make for that?
- Oh, no, no, no, I know this.
- Hot apple cider with cinnamon sticks?
- Hot apple cider with cinnamon sticks.
What the frig, Cooper?
We were supposed to be in my office
half an hour ago.
And yet now you're in my office.
Point Cooper.
Welcome to the thunderdome, Kripke.
We agreed to exchange copies of our work.
Let me see yours.
Why don't you show me yours first?
You think I just fell off the turnip truck?
We exchange at the same time.
How do I know you're not going
to take my ideas and publish them?
How do I know you're not gonna?
Yeah, because I'm not interested
in getting published in MAD Magazine.
The zingers fly fast
in the thunderdome, Barry.
Are we gonna do this or not?
Thank you. So we read each other's work
and meet again tomorrow?
Fine.
Nice try. This is blank paper.
And I'm sure it's still more valuable
than whatever's in here.
- Cough it up, Cooper.
- Very well.
If this one's blank too,
I'm gonna be furious.
Fine.
Yo, always bet on black.
Get that waste of money out of my face.
It's only a waste of money
if we don't play with them.
He's right, dog.
Please, I'm working.
You know, there is a way we
can get action figures to look exactly like us.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
Two words: 3D printer.
But maybe it's three words.
No, hang on. Okay.
One word, a letter and a number,
and maybe a hyphen.
3D printer.
I have always wanted a 3D printer.
Of course you have.
They're an engineer's dream.
Anything you can design,
a 3D printer can make out of plastic.
Yeah, but they're so expensive.
Oh, come on, you deserve one.
You've worked hard to find a woman
who makes a lot of money.
Well, the prices have been coming down.
Oh, true.
They're practically giving them away.
You know, in exchange for money.
And we could make stuff we need
for work with it.
Prototypes of my CAD/CAM designs,
specialized tools.
Not to mention Malibu Koothrappali
and his totally bitching dream house.
We don't need
Malibu Koothrappali's dream house.
Really, smart guy? Where is he supposed
to park his sweet little Corvette?
The monkey in my tobacco study
has taken to smoking a pipe.
I'm supposed to remove his brain
to examine...
...but it's hard, because now
he reminds me of my uncle.
You've been awfully quiet tonight.
Is everything okay?
I'm fine.
All right. Well, how was work today?
Did you exchange your research
with Kripke?
Yes.
Sheldon, what's going on?
I read his research and...
...it's leaps and bounds ahead of mine.
Which means the mommy
of the smartest physicist at the university...
...is not my mommy as I had thought.
It's his mommy.
Sheldon, I wish there was something
I could do to make you feel better.
May I offer you a consoling hug?
What do we have to lose?
How's that?
I feel like I'm being strangled
by a boa constrictor.
Why'd you stop?
Come on, Sheldon, we're gonna be late.
I can't go in today, I'm sick.
You're not sick.
You don't wanna face Kripke.
No. Look.
One hundred and 28.
See?
- What did you do? Put this in your tea?
- Oh, dear.
Now I'm not even smarter than you.
Sheldon, Kripke is not smarter than you.
You just got stuck on a wrong path.
Happened to Einstein. He got stuck
in the unified field theory for decades.
Oh, don't play the Einstein card.
His breakthroughs happened
when no one knew anything.
Everything was a great breakthrough.
Sheldon Lee Cooper,
I do not have time for this nonsense.
Go put your clothes on,
get in the car, and let's go to work.
All right, jeez.
What a grouch.
How did I do that?
I gotta remember how I did that.
Do you realize by owning a 3D printer...
...we are reclaiming
the manufacturing process...
...and taking jobs back
from sweatshops in China.
I think this thing was made in China.
Eh, what can you do?
Ooh, I think it's done.
It worked.
We printed a whistle.
Amazing.
You realize these things go
for 25 cents a pop at a party store.
And we made it in only three hours.
- Sounds just like store-bought.
- Heh, heh.
Okay, give me a superhero pose...
...and I will scan you into the computer
for your action figure.
Oh, I wish I was in better shape.
Stop holding your stomach in,
I'll give you a six-pack with the computer.
Oh, okay, great.
Now, I can look like Val Kilmer
as Batman...
...instead of Val Kilmer
as he looks today.
All right. You can suck it in a little bit.
Cooper, we have a problem.
Your work is really not
at the level I expected it to be.
I know. Go ahead and mock me.
But use small words so I understand.
Don't play dumb with me.
We both know what your problem is.
- We do?
- You have a girlfriend.
- So?
- So my work would suffer too...
...if I was getting laid all the time.
Yes.
That is the reason.
My work is suffering because of...
...all the laid I'm getting.
You lucky bastard.
What can I say?
You know, she enjoys my genitals.
I am giving them to her
on a nightly basis.
Okay, stop bragging.
You had some brilliant insights in here.
But if we'll make this work...
...you need to buckle down and focus.
- Yeah, I'll do what I can.
But it's not going to be easy
because when I'm with Amy...
...and our bathing suit areas
mush together...
...because it... Boy, howdy... . Is it magic.
Oh, good, you're home.
Got a little surprise for you.
Oh!
Say hello to my little friend.
Oh, my God, it's so cute.
I didn't think there could be
a smaller version of you.
I know, right?
And thanks to photographs
and a little 3D modeling...
...here comes the bride.
- Oh, Howie, I love these.
- I thought you might.
- Were they expensive?
- It didn't cost a thing. I made them myself.
- How?
- Koothrappali and I...
...bought a used 3D printer for $5000.
Heh, heh.
Five thousand dollars for a couple of dolls?
Are you out of your mind?
Not just a couple of dolls.
For as many dolls as we want.
And whistles.
At any point did it dawn on you to talk
to me about spending this kind of money?
It's kind of dawning on me now.
I don't believe you.
Howie, we can't afford to waste money
on junk like this.
What are you talking about?
We make plenty of money.
I make plenty of money.
You make peanuts.
Well, yes, but we're married now.
That means when you get sick,
I take care of you.
And when you make a bunch of money...
...I get to buy stuff.
Sorry if you don't like it,
but that's how love works.
No. Here's how love works.
You're gonna return the machine...
...or you could print out a working set
of lady parts and sleep with those.
Oh, my God.
Are you actually thinking about it?
I don't understand.
Why didn't you just tell Kripke the truth?
Because the truth made me look bad.
Whereas a ridiculous bald-faced lie
makes me look good.
Anyway, if Kripke asks...
...tell him my coitus with Amy is frequent,
intense and whimsically inventive.
Is my coitus whimsically inventive?
That is what I write
on the bathroom walls.
"For a whimsically inventive time,
call Leonard Hofstadter."
I know you're joking,
but I'd be okay with that.
- Sheldon, can I ask you a question?
- Of course.
Are you ever gonna sleep with Amy?
- That's awfully personal.
- We don't ask Sheldon things like that.
Maybe you don't, I do. What's the deal?
Well, word around the university is...
...I'm giving her sex organs
a properjostling.
All right, come on, be serious.
You have been going out a long time.
She would clearly like
to have a physical relationship with you.
So, what are you doing?
All right, we're down the rabbit hole.
What are you doing?
Well, first of all, I'm quite fond of Amy.
Then what's the problem?
Penny...
...all my life I have been uncomfortable...
...with the sort of physical contact
that comes easily to others...
...handshaking, hugging...
...prostate exams.
But I'm working on it, you know?
Just recently, I had to put VapoRub
on Amy's chest.
A year ago,
that would have been unthinkable.
Now you know how I feel
when I have to put it on you.
Okay, hang on.
Are you saying
someday you and Amy might...
...actually get physical?
It's a possibility.
Oh, my God.
Sheldon, I know this wasn't easy
and I'm glad we can have this conversation.
- Hey.
- Oh, my God.
Sure you wanna do this?
- Give up your half of the 3D printer?
- Yes.
And can you please make that out
to Bernadette?
I was taken off the joint account
until I learn the value of money.
Well, that's harsh.
Tell me about it.
Aren't you gonna eat lunch?
No, I blew my food allowance
on Pokemon cards.
Well, the equation balances,
but it's certainly not elegant.
Whatever. You get any last night?
Yes.
Gave it to her good, huh?
No, I gave it to her well.
Now, over here I was thinking...
...turbulence could be reduced if we put...
- Yeah, yeah.
Was she naked,
or was she wearing lingerie?
I didn't notice.
How could you not notice?
I was too busy squishing
all the desirable parts of her body.
Oh, you're killing me, Cooper!
Can we get back to work?
Sure, sure, sure.
You guys ever used any toys?
Toys?
I do have a model rocket next to my bed.
A rocket? You're a freak. I love it.