Eddie, get your surfboard
in the car.
We're ready for the beach.
Okay, Mom.
Well, I'm all set.
With a little luck, I might dig
up a couple of old friends.
Is the hamper all
packed, Aunt Lily? Yes.
I even brought
a jar of ants.
(Grandpa) Good idea. Yes.
It would be just our luck
to get there...
and have none of the little dears
show up and spoil our picnic.
Here comes Pop.
Pop, are you really going to go
swimming when we get to Paradise Cove?
When we get
to Paradise Cove...
I'm gonna swim out way over
my head and everything.
You can meet up with some very interesting
things way out in the briny deep.
So much for the national news.
We have a report of a Russian trawler in
local waters right off Paradise Cove.
So far, they've stayed beyond
the three-mile limit...
and they claim to be fishing.
But who knows what the results of this
little fishing expedition may be.
What a beautiful spot.
Yes.
But it certainly
was strange, dear.
Those hundreds of people running
off the beach just as we arrived.
Well, it's probably just another
one of those jellyfish scares.
Herman, where are you going?
Hmm?
Where are you going?
[laughing]
I'm going
scuba diving, dear.
And if I run into
any tasty-looking scubas...
I'll spear one, we can clean
it, and have it for supper.
Come on, Grandpa.
Let's find a spot where I
can bury you in the sand.
Okay, Eddie,
but this time bury me deep.
I don't want any crazy dogs
digging me up like last time.
(announcer) That Russian trawler
spotted off our coast...
is still in the vicinity
of Paradise Cove.
They have their nets out and they are
still beyond the three-mile limit.
Well, good fishing, comrades.
Come on, Grandpa.
Okay, let's go.
[exclaims]
These wolf burgers
are almost done.
Eddie, go down to the water and
call your father for lunch.
And by the way...
where did you bury Grandpa?
I sort of forget.
He's around here someplace.
Hey, Dad!
Dad!
Mom, I don't see
Pop anywhere.
Nonsense, Eddie.
He's right over there...
[exclaims]
Heavens to Betsy,
he's gone!
Oh, dear. I hope
nothing's happened to him.
I knew I shouldn't have let him go
in the water without his sea horsie.
Aunt Lily,
what are we going to do?
Eddie, here, take this and
poke around for your grandpa.
[Grandpa yells]
I think I found him.
Can't a body even get
some shuteye around here?
Grandpa, something's happened.
We think that Herman's been
washed out to sea.
So what's the problem?
He's Sanforized.
We've got to find him.
I hope a whale
hasn't eaten my pop.
I wanted him to help me
with my homework tonight.
Why did he take up
that silly scuba diving hobby?
You know, Lily, when Herman
gets caught up in a hobby...
he really gets
caught up in it.
Good night.
[speaking Russian]
[both speaking Russian]
Well...
[chuckles]
Scuba dooba do.
Oh, yeah? Well, the
same to you, Charlie.
What did the Bureau of Missing
Persons say, Grandpa?
Well, they say
that Herman didn't qualify.
Didn't qualify?
He's missing, isn't he?
He qualifies as missing,
but when I described him...
they said he didn't
qualify as a person.
Oh!
My poor pussycat.
Where, oh, where can he be?
[Speaking Spanish]
[speaking Russian]
[speaking French]
I don't know how I'm gonna
make you chaps understand me.
You speak English!
[exclaims]
Well, isn't it
a small world.
Yes, I speak English.
Me speak English.
[laughing]
Well...
Where did you learn it?
On the TV.
We watch Russian reruns,
Dobie Gil/is.
I'll be darned. TV.
It certainly is a great medium
for cultural exchange.
[speaking Russian]
You very valuable
anthropological find.
Thank you.
I do my best.
[giggling]
Uh...
Say, listen, have you fellas
heard any good jokes lately?
I heard a keen one
the other day:
What has four wheels
and flies?
[chuckling]
Could be new secret weapon.
Come on.
You're supposed to ask me, "What
has four wheels and flies?"
Okay, sea monster.
What has four wheels
and flies?
A garbage truck.
A garbage truck?
Garbage truck.
[all laughing]
[speaking Russian]
Say, listen.
You're a very good group.
Here's another one
that'll really grab you.
Trawler number 47.
Reports finding missing link near
the United States of America.
Definitely puts Russians ahead
in missing link race.
Please advise.
Composite picture en route...
to Commissar on missing links.
Answer immediately.
This report top-secret.
Repeat. Top-secret.
I've just got
a Russian top-secret.
First one of the day.
Good work. What is it?
That's from a Russian trawler
just off our coast.
They radioed Moscow.
They found a missing link
in their fishing net.
Claim it's
a scientific breakthrough.
What's this missing link
look like?
Here is a composite we just drew up from
the Russian ship's description of it.
I can't imagine...
[bell ringing] what that's
the missing link to.
Just a minute.
Moscow is sending another top-secret
back to the Russian ship.
"Stupid idiots.
"From your description,
this is not missing link.
"You have obviously captured
new kind of American spy."
An American spy.
You'd better get this over to the
State Department right away.
They won't be back from lunch yet.
It's only 3:00.
That's a chance we're going to have to take.
Go on and get over there.
How often do the Russians
capture an American spy?
This is an emergency.
Yes, sir.
Well, Grandpa,
Herman is nowhere to be found.
Have you gotten anything
on that crystal ball of yours?
Wait a minute.
I'm adjusting
the fine tunings.
Hold it.
I think
I'm getting something now.
What is it?
I see an ocean.
I see a boat.
Do you see Pop?
Now hold it.
It's coming in clear now.
There he is. I see Herman.
What's he doing?
He's on a ship...
and he is leading up a bunch of
funny-looking men in community singing.
That's ridiculous.
But, Lily, I saw it.
It was right there.
That crystal ball
has never been the same...
since Spot sat on it for three
days and tried to hatch it.
♪ Down by the station I'
♪ Early in the morning ♪
♪ See the little
puffer bellies ♪
♪ Standing in a row ♪
♪ See the engine driver ♪
♪ Pulling on his throttle ♪
♪ Toot, toot! ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet! ♪
♪ Offwe go ♪
Now, everybody.
♪ See the engine driver ♪
♪ pulling on his throttle ♪
♪ Toot, toot! ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet! ♪
♪ Off we go N'
[laughing]
Herman, you've got
to stop singing.
Why? What's the matter?
Was I off-key?
I just contact Moscow
on the wireless.
Do you know
what you are, Herman?
What I am?
I get it. It's gonna
be one of those jokes.
No, Valeiry, what am I?
You are a spy.
A SPY?
Valeiry, are you sure
of this?
Moscow wired me
this morning.
Our missing link
is international spy.
But I not want
to tell you...
until after you finished that
lovely song about the puffer belly.
But I think
there must be some mistake.
If I was an international spy, I think
someone would have let me know.
(Charlie) I've been in the State
Department over 15 years...
and never saw a spy this ugly.
Yeah, Charlie, but you never know what new
gimmick the top brass might have come up with.
I guess you're right.
We'd better check it out and see which
department launched this project.
This may be
top-secret stuff.
And that's a classified face,
if I ever saw one.
[phone ringing]
Humpty Dumpty sat on the wall,
the Cisco Kid is having a ball.
Never mind, John.
You don't have to use
the code. It's me, Charlie.
I just wanted to know...
if that thing the Russians say they
captured could be one of our agents.
Impossible. Impossible.
You, uh...
You've never seen him
around here, have you?
No, sir.
Well, then this is obviously
a crude Russian hoax.
Pass that on. This is definitely
Dawson, this is just
a crude Russian hoax.
"State Department exposes
crude Russian hoax.
"Story of spy
on Russian trawler a fake.
"No such person exists."
Look, they have
Pop's picture in the paper.
That's my Herman.
That Russian trawler we heard
about on the radio.
They must have
picked up Herman.
How could a grown man go out
for a harmless little swim...
and wind up being captured
by the Russians as a spy?
I'll admit it's difficult,
but in all the world...
only my son-in-law has the talent
to do anything that stupid.
"Russian spy story a fake."
Oh, to be embarrassed in front of
our glorious leader like this.
By the way, who is our
glorious leader this month?
Never mind.
I know who our glorious leader is.
I was just testing you.
What message should I send to
the fishing boat, Commissar?
To think that Mother Russia
should be embarrassed...
in front of
the whole world like this.
Here is the message
I want you to send:
Whatever you have found,
missing link...
deep-sea creature...
whatever this ugly,
ugly thing is...
do not bring it back.
[clearing throat]
Get rid of it immediately.
Dump it into the ocean or
whatever, but get rid of it.
I have your message,
Commissar.
"Russian Pipe Dream."
[exclaiming]
Stroke.
Grandpa, do you think
we're doing the right thing?
I tell you, Lily,
this is the only way.
If the State Department
won't help us...
we'll have to rescue
Herman ourselves.
I guess you're right.
But we better hurry.
There's no telling what those
people will do to Herman.
He's so defenseless.
Do you think the Russians
will brainwash him?
If they do,
I hope they're careful.
I'd hate to have a son-in-law
with a dishpan brain.
Thank you.
Thank you, friends.
You heard the message
from the Commissar?
Herman has got to go.
Yeah, but who's got the heart
to tell him?
(Herman)
Now, ladies and gentleman...
I have plan.
We give Comrade Herman
farewell party.
I see.
We kiss him on both cheeks
and then we shoot him.
[speaking Russian]
He's too nice guy
for Russki farewell party.
We give him nice, decadent
American farewell party.
Like in MGM musical.
Good, we have much singing,
dancing, laughing.
After that, all of a sudden,
we shuffle him off to Buffalo.
(man)
Hey!
[feet stomping]
(man)
Hey!
Listen, Grandpa.
They're torturing poor Herman.
Do you think
he'll be able to hold out?
Don't worry, Lily.
He's got nerves of steel.
Yes, but I just hope they
don't rust in this damp air.
N[music playing]
It was a fine idea we give
Herman farewell party, Gregor.
It was only way
we could get him to leave.
It's times like this I'm glad
I'm a Lawrence Welk fan.
Notchey, baby,
you're a gasser.
And I thought
he was in danger.
And what do I find?
Herman-a-go-go.
Lily, maybe
they are there torturing him.
I mean, that's not exactly Juliet
Prowse he's wiggling his watusi with.
Well, I'll put a stop
to that.
They just don't build these
things like they used to.
(Lily)
Herman?
(Herman)
Lily.
[stuttering]
And Grandpa.
What are you doing out here
in the middle of the ocean?
That's what
we'd like to ask you.
Who are they?
You read
your propaganda booklets.
They're capitalistic tools
of Wall Street.
In the books
they wasn't green.
You know what I think?
I think that you are just
a carousing playboy...
and so are all
of your wild friends.
Just playboys.
Playboys! Playboys!
No, Lily,
that one's a girl.
Herman, I'm ashamed of you.
My son-in-law,
the dirty old man.
Herman,
you are coming with me.
Yes, dear.
But, lady, we're only having
a little farewell party.
Well, farewell to you.
You just take
your yacht of corruption...
and revelry and sail on,
home wreckers.
Don't talk that way
in front of my friends.
Herman, come along.
Well, fellas, Notchey,
goodbye.
If you're ever in Mockingbird
Heights, look me up.
That's what Americans
are really like.
Holy mackerel,
what party poopers!
Let's go.
N[music playing]
Lily, won't you
let me explain?
Grandpa...
will you tell that miserable person on
the couch that I am not speaking to him?
Miserable person
on the couch...
your wife
is not speaking to you.
You hear that, you fathead?
Please, Grandpa,
just translate.
Never mind
the editorial comment.
Even I'm surprised at you.
I never thought my dear, sweet,
kind uncle would go ape.
Well, golly-gee. How would you like it
if you were pulled out of the ocean...
in a fishnet
and dumped into a hole...
and have a bunch of people
think you were a missing link?
I tell you that sort of thing is
very damaging to your psyche.
[scoffs]
Why were you carousing
with those people?
Well, Lily, I was just trying to be one
of the boys and friendly and all that.
After all, dear, I am a member of the
Junior Chamber of Commerce, you know.
You've just got
to forgive me.
The way they do on television
every afternoon...
on The Guiding Light.
Go ahead, Lily.
Make up with the big slob
before he starts blubbering...
and washes all the furniture
out into the street again.
Well, all right.
I forgive you.
Thank you, dear.
That's real wizard of you.
But I want you to forget about
those Russian friends of yours...
and all of that singing
and dancing and carrying on.
I certainly will, dear.
I promise.
All right.
Now, come on upstairs,
we'd all better get to bed.
I'll be up in a minute,
sweetheart.
[sighs]
♪ Down by the station ♪
♪ Early in the morning ♪
♪ See the little
puffer bellies ♪
♪ Standing in a row N'
Hey!