Here's the okay
from Washington...
on our latest
ham operator application.
Call letters are W6XRL4.
These two-way radio rigs
are getting to be
quite a popular hobby.
Yeah. I just hope
this man realizes...
that being able to communicate
with people all over the world
carries a serious responsibility.
Mm. What's the name on this one?
Uh, "Herman Munster.
Mockingbird Heights."
Oh, I'm sure he's a solid citizen
with both feet on the ground.
? One bright and shining light?
? That taught me wrong from right?
? I found in my mother's eyes??
[Airwave Static, Transmission Ends]
[Switches Clicking]
That's funny.
The man in Australia cut me off
in the middle of"My Mother's Eyes."
[Airwave Static]
Oh, Herman.
Will you knock it off
with that thing?
Look, if you wanna communicate
with people around the world,
here, use my crystal ball.
You put over $400
into that thing,
and you can't even get
the roller derby on it.
Yes, Herman, come on to bed.
You've talked to six countries,
and nobody wants to hear
"My Mother's Eyes."
I'll come to bed later.
Lily, I've always wanted
a ham radio set.
And now that I've got one,
I'm gonna listen in on distress signals...
and notify the authorities and...
prevent disasters...
and noble things like that.
Aw, Uncle Herman,
you're all heart.
Oh, no, I'm not.
There's lots of other junk in here.
Come on, Marilyn.
Let's go upstairs.
Look, Herman, take my advice.
Don't try to be noble.
Just learn to mind your own business.
That's just what I've been doing...
ever since I told that Napoleon fellow
to take that shortcut through Waterloo.
[Switches Clicking]
[Airwave Static]
[Man Over Radio]
Calling W6XRL4.
Grandpa. That's me!
That's-That's me!
[Switch Clicks]
Hello, hello?
This is W6XRL4.
Come in, come in.
[Switch Clicks]
[Man Over Radio]
This is Milan, Italy.
Italy.
Are you the one...
who was singing
"My Mother's Eyes"?
[Switch Clicks]
That was me.
That was me. Hmm!
That is correct.
[Switch Clicks]
[Man Giving Raspberry]
That is all.
Over and out.
[Laughing]
Well, I don't call that
very neighborly.
[Airwave Static]
Calling CQ.
Uh, come in, please.
[Switch Clicks]
[Airwave Static]
How do you like
these new walkie-talkies
that I got for my birthday?
Boy, they're great.
We can play
some neat games with them.
Let me have one.
Okay.
Aw, they're no fun. I'd rather go home
and watch my Grandpa blow up things.
Aw, go on, Eddie.
I don't think you have
half the fun at home you say you do.
Hey, Walt, you go over
on the other side of the wall,
and we can talk to each other.
We'll pretend we're spacemen.
Okay.
Can you read me?
I read you loud and clear.
Over.
Hey, where you goin', Eddie?
Aw, I'm goin' home.
This is kid stuff.
See ya later, Roger.
Bye, Walt.
You know, sometimes
I just don't dig that Eddie.
Me too.
I wouldn't mess around with him
except for the neat way
he opens up cans...
with his ears.
Hey, Walt. I got an idea.
Why don't I be a spaceship,
and you be a control tower
on Mars?
Okay.
Get over there
behind the wall.
[Clears Throat]
[Lowers Voice]
This is spaceship X-14.
Now circling spaceport.
Come in, spaceport.
[Airwave Static]
[Switch Clicking]
[Switches Clicking]
[Static Continues]
Ah.
[Switch Clicks]
[Walt Over Radio]
This is Spaceport Mars
calling X-14.
Tracking you on gamma beam.
Stand by at plutonium layer
for landing instructions.
Mars.
[Transmission Breaking Up]
This is spaceship X-14.
Vector reading: 9-0-3.
Now firing retro-rockets
in sequence.
It is Mars.
It is Mars!
That's a spaceship!
[Switch Clicks]
Hello! Hello! Hello!
This is W6XRL4, planet Earth.
Hey, Walt.
What's this "planet Earth"junk?
What do you mean?
Listen.
[Switch Clicks]
This is W6X4L...
W6XRL4, planet Earth.
Calling Mars.
[Switch Clicks]
Some other kid must have
one of these things, too,
and he's trying
to get in on the game.
Yeah, but it's getting late.
We gotta get home.
Just a minute. Just a minute.
[Clears Throat]
[Lowers Voice]
Planet Earth,
this is spaceship X-14.
Now in landing pattern
for Spaceport 7, Mars.
Will have to break off.
[Switch Clicks]
But you can't break off.
L-I've gotta talk to you.
Please, fella, don't break off.
[Switch Clicks]
Sorry. Will resume transmission
same time tomorrow,
4:00 Earth time.
That is all.
[Switch Clicks]
But...
I got Mars.
I got Mars!
[Whoops]
And Lily and Grandpa
said this was a kid's toy.
Hah! Wait till I break this news
to the world.
[Laughing]
Your Majesty,
ladies and gentlemen,
it is with a great deal of pleasure
that I modestly accept...
this Nobel Prize in Science.
[Laughing]
Herman!
Will you please come to bed?
I'm dying to get some sleep.
Lily, I'm much too excited to go...
to go to sleep.
And besides,
I just may be sitting on top...
of one of the biggest
scientific breakthroughs in history.
[Chuckling]
Well, whatever it is you're sitting on,
get up off it and come to bed.
Lily, I was speaking figuratively.
And that's no way to talk
to a future Nobel Prize winner.
Oh, Herman.!
Come to bed.!
Yes, dear.
[Snoring]
[Continues Snoring]
Herman.
Herman. Herman!
[Yelps]
Oh! Oh, Grandpa.
You gave me such a fright.
I thought you were
a man from Mars.
What are you talking about,
Herman?
What's going on down here?
You've been sitting down here
for hours.
Grandpa.
What would you say...
if I told you that in two minutes...
at the stroke of 4:00...
I, Herman Munster,
am gonna be in communication
with the planet Mars?
[Laughing]
I'd say...
that if you keep talking this way,
they'll take you away
to the funny farm.
[Ringing]
There.
Now. It's 4:00.
You'll see. You'll see.
[Laughs]
[Switch Clicks]
[Airwave Static]
Boy, Roger, we'll have more fun
playing spacemen than ever...
now that your father bought you
this genuine synthetic
plastic spaceship.
Boy, I hope we can get that kid
who we talked to yesterday
on the walkie-talkie.
We said we'd call him back at 4:00.
[Clears Throat]
[Lowers Voice]
Calling W6XRL4.
Come in, Earth.
This is Mars.
I've got them!
Are you trying to tell me
that's Mars?
[Switch Clicks]
It's not the weather report.
Hello, Mars?
This is W6XRL4.
Where are you?
[Switch Clicks]
We have just penetrated
through substratosphere...
and made our first landing
on Earth. Over.
[Switch Clicks]
They're here!
They-They've landed
on Earth!
All right.
All right, Herman.
Don't get so excited.
It's only people from Mars.
People from Mars?
Grandpa! Grandpa!
[Switch Clicks]
Don't go away.
I'll be right back.
Grandpa. Grandpa.
Grandpa.
Will you wake up,
you dummy!
We're making history.
Hello. Hello.
Come in, Earth.
I guess somethin' happened
to our friend from Earth.
Maybe the kid's parents made him
go take a bath or somethin'.
Aw, let's come back after supper.
Maybe we can get him then.
You really think it's a kid?
He must be.
He sounds so stupid.
Now, Grandpa, Grandpa.
You heard them.
They're men from Mars,
and they've landed on Earth.
We have to go call the air force.
They have a department that checks
on unidentified flying objects.
Not so fast, Herman.
We can't just go
and call the air force.
You want 'em to think
we're a couple of nuts?
Oh. Heavens, no.
Before we call the air force,
we have to have concrete evidence.
But where are we
gonna get evidence?
All we have to go by
is a voice on the radio.
Don't worry, Herman.
I'll find that spaceship
with my direction finder.
Come on.
I've got it in here somewhere.
Let me see.
What do we have here?
Oh. A rabbit's foot
carried by General Custer.
Mother's Day card
from Lizzie Borden.
Compass off the Titanic.
Ah! Here it is!
[Laughing]
Yeah!
My radio direction finder.
Direction finder?
Grandpa, that's just
an old-fashioned divining rod.
True, true.
But I had it transistorized
last month.
Grandpa.
Yeah?
If we find this spaceship,
you and I will be famous
all over the world.
[Both Laughing]
Hey, Mom.
How come Grandpa and Dad
aren't having dinner with us?
Well, Grandpa said
they had to go out tonight
on important business.
But Grandpa didn't even
take his shovel.
Something's up, Aunt Lily.
They weren't their usual selves.
They looked very strange
when they went out.
I don't know what's the matter,
but Herman's been acting funny
ever since he got that ham radio set.
Oh, but he does need a hobby.
He works hard all week.
[Sighs]
That's true, Marilyn.
You know,
Herman took up golf once,
but he had so much trouble
getting together a foursome.
Hey, Mom, maybe Dad's
out playing poker with some men.
When he comes home,
you'll have to yell at him
and make him sleep on the sofa.
- Eddie. Where do you get
ideas like that?
- From television.
You see, Marilyn,
it's just the way I told you.
Those shows on television
about horrible families
have a definite effect on children.
[Steady Clicking]
Grandpa, we've been
following that divining rod
for over an hour now,
and we haven't seen
a Martian yet.
Don't worry, Herman.
We'll find that spaceship
before the night's over.
Well, I certainly hope so.
The only thing it's led us to so far
is a shortwave diathermy machine.
That lady looked very upset
when she saw us
peering in her window.
Will you stop worrying, Herman?
She'll be down off the chandelier
before morning.
[Loud Clicking]
Look, Herman!
It's found something.
[Laughing]
You see?
I told you it'd work.
[Laughing]
Grandpa, they're down there.
Right.
The Martians
are hiding down there.
[Chuckles]
Hi, Martians.
Are you down there?
[Clicking Stops]
[Gasping]
You big dummy!
Why didn't you tell me
it was set for "Water"?
What are ya squawking about?
You could've got a face full of scrap iron.
Calling W6XRL4.
This is spaceship X-14.
Would somebody come in?
Would somebody
please come in? Please?
Gee, Rog, I wonder
where that other kid is.
He hasn't been on the air
since 4:00.
Maybe he's a little shrimp
and can't stay out this late.
Let's keep on trying
for a little while longer.
[Clicking]
[Clicking Louder]
Hey, Herman.
We're getting something.
Look. It's over here.
Oh, boy!
I hope it's not
another false alarm.
Come on.
Look! Herman, a spaceship.
Grandpa.
We're making history.
We're Galileo, Columbus
and David Susskind
all rolled into one.
Look, Herman.
There are two Martians
by the ship,
and look how little
they are.
Just like in the comic strips.
Come on.
We'll welcome them to planet Earth.
Hello there!
Ahoy, Martians!
[Screaming]
Go! Go!
They ran away.
I guess they're just
not used to Earth people,
but can you imagine anyone
being afraid of us?
Well, maybe their standards of beauty
aren't as high as ours.
Grandpa.
What?
I'm getting scared.
Those Martians might come back
with a ray gun and disintegrate us.
I'd feel like a perfect fool
if they did.
Let's at least get
some concrete evidence.
We'll take a picture of the ship
we can show to the air force.
Good idea.
Say "cheese."
Will you knock it off
and take the picture!
"Cheese."
Hmm.
And you say you and your son-in-law
took this photo last night.
That's right, Captain.
You see, he's been in voice communication
with Mars for the past few days.
You mean he's been talking
to the little people up there.
Yes. He has a ham radio.
A radio.
That must have made it a lot easier.
Oh, of course. As soon as the Martians
told us that they were going to land,
I got out my divining rod
to help track them down.
You have a divining rod.
Yes, and it's transistorized.
All I have to do
is set it for "Martians,"
and it led us to their spaceship
on a vacant lot.
There were two little men there,
and, as soon as they saw us,
they ran away.
I wonder why.
You see, I don't know either,
but we felt it our patriotic duty
to bring it to the attention
of the government.
Well, I can't tell you how much
we appreciate your coming in here...
and taking up our time
like this.
What?
[Stammering]
You mean that's it?
We discover a spaceship
and Martians,
and it's just "How do you do,
hello and good-bye"?
Oh, no. I can assure you
that this photo will be processed
through proper channels.
Uh, Captain, if you don't mind,
this is very important to me.
- I'll wait outside.
- Excellent.
Sergeant, come in, please.
Aunt Lily, that was
Uncle Herman's boss on the phone.
They're looking for him
down at work.
He didn't even
go to work today, Marilyn.
He's playing
with that ham radio again.
They said they were taking inventory
down at the parlor,
and Uncle Herman's the only one
who knows where things are.
Hello? This is W6XRL4
calling spaceship X-14.
Come in, please.
[Switch Clicks]
[Airwave Static]
X-14, X-14.
Come in, come in,
wherever you are.
We were standin' here
playing Martian last night, Pop,
and those two big guys
came along.
They had on real scary masks
and yelled at us,
and one of them
was carrying a big stick.
Why, they oughta be
ashamed of themselves.
One thing I can't stand
is a wise guy bully.
Listen, Roger, I want...
[Herman Over Walkie-Talkie]
Calling X-14. Come in, please.
Come in, please.
That's the guy now, Pop.
Here, give me that thing.
Hello. This is X-14.
[Switch Clicks]
Oh, I'm so very glad I got you.
It was very rude of you
to run away last night.
[Switch Clicks]
- Look, who is this?
- [Switch Clicks]
Why, I'm W6XRL4,
one of the Earth people.
You sound very, uh, big.
Are you the head Martian?
[Switch Clicks]
Yeah, I'm the head Martian.
You know what I'm gonna do, buster?
If I ever run into you,
I'm gonna break your arm off
and shove it down your throat!
[Switch Clicks]
Hmm.
Well-Well, you just
can't do that, Mr. Martian,
because you don't know
where I am.
So there.
Well, in that case, I guess I'll just
have to blow up the planet Earth.
Oh, my goodness!
Lily! Lily! Lily!
The world's coming to an end.
And it's... And it's all my fault.
[Whimpering]
There, there, dear.
Herman?
Lily?
Is anybody home?
Marilyn?
Herman, what are you doing?
Grandpa, the world's
coming to an end,
and we're hiding out
till it's over.
Herman, will you
let us out of here!
He keeps talking about men from Mars
blowing up the world.
It's true, Grandpa.
While you were out,
I talked to the head Martian,
and he got mad at me and started
calling me names and said
he was gonna blow up the world.
Herman, will you
pipe down a minute and listen?
That was no spaceship we found.
The air force identified it
as a child's toy...
sold in every department store.
And those two Martians we saw?
It wasn't them.
It was two kids playing spacemen.
- You're kidding.
- Kidding?
Look.
"Made in Japan"?
There you are, Herman.
No Martians, no spaceship,
no end of the world.
Now what do you have
to say for yourself?
Well,
that's the way
the ball bounces.
[Airwave Static]
[Switch Clicking]
What's this, a delegation?
We just came down here
to get you away from that radio.
That's right, Herman.
It's caused us nothing but trouble.
Don't worry. I'm just trying
to get some music so I can relax.
Maybe Lawrence Welk
or someone.
But, Uncle Herman...
[Man Over Radio]
Come in, spaceport.
Come in, please.
This is spaceship Astro-70
calling Mars.
Calling Mars.
[Airwave Static]
Hmm!
Will you listen to that?
[Switch Clicking]
Hello, spaceship Astro-70.
Spaceship Astro-70.
This is Earth.
Lay off it, you big dummy!
[Laughing]
No one's gonna fool me
the second time.
[Laughing]
My, those Earth people
are getting rude.