Lily, don't you think Marilyn
should be up in bed?
I mean, she looks terrible...
with all that color in her cheeks
and everything.
She was sent home from school
about an hour ago.
Oh! She has a fever... 98.6.
But... But isn't that normal, Aunt Lily?
Oh, heavens, no.
Uh, we Munsters average
in the low 50s.
Hey, Dad.
Grandpa's down in the dungeon
waiting to mix up a cure.
Here.
Grandpa, now hear this.
I read you, Herman.
High fever.
And I feel so low.
Feels very low.
There.
[Chuckles]
That oughta lift her spirits.
Oh. Tell him to forget it.
Tell him to forget it.
Grandpa, forget it.
Oh.
Oh, I guess you're right
about Grandpa's cures.
He should either give up medicine
or take up practice in California.
Oh, you poor dear.
We'd better put her upstairs in bed
before Grandpa has her floating
all over the neighborhood.
Can I help you, Lily?
Oh, no, thank you, dear.
Oh, yes.
Uh... Uh, maybe.
Uh, Marilyn was going
to the bank for me.
Do you think I could trust you
to make a withdrawal?
Trust me?
How could a levelheaded,
conscientious fellow like me
get in trouble at the bank?
Oh, Herman, here's the bankbook.
It's just a simple withdrawal.
Yes, dear.
Uh, but I think you'd better
take Grandpa to the bank with you.
Hmm. Well, I would prefer
to make a withdrawal
at the blood bank,
but I guess you can't
have everything.
Now, Herman,
Yes, dear.
The withdrawal slip is all made out.
Mm-hmm.
We have
a tax installment due...
Right.
So we need all the money
from the tax account.
Right. Uh, draw out
all the money.
Yes.
Uh, my hat, please.
Thank you.
And, Herman...
Yes, dear?
Bring it straight back here.
[Chuckles Softly]
Gotcha. Grandpa.
You wanted to see me,
Mr. Grover?
Yes, Williams.
I just had another report
on those masked bandits who've been
terrorizing this side of town.
They held up our main office
this morning. We may be next.
They the ones
with the Halloween masks?
Yes, those hideous disguises
are their trademark.
I'll warn all my tellers, sir.
Okay, but these men are always heavily armed,
and I don't want anybody hurt.
You know my rule here.
If this bank is held up,
you tell our people to turn over the money.
That's much better than having
one of our personnel
or our customers shot.
Okay, Mr. Grover.
I'll inform the tellers.
Excuse me, miss.
Yes, sir? May I help...
[Gasps]
I'd like all the money.
Uh, miss, would you
put it in a bag or something?
It... It's hard to carry
loose like that.
Oh, thank you, miss.
Uh, you give very quick service.
It's a pleasure doing business
with you.
Bye.
You know, Herman,
I didn't realize Lily had
that much money in her tax account.
I know. As the hipsters say,
that's quite a bagful of bread.
Maybe you oughta count it
while we're waiting for Lily.
Count it?
Good idea.
They might have robbed us.
18,100.
18,200.
$18,300.
Herman, I have some news for you.
Yes, dear?
We only had $680
in our tax account.
Really?
Really.
You know what this means,
now, don't you?
Yes, I do, dear.
It means our bank gives
a very generous rate of interest.
It means, Herman,
that you have goofed it again.
But, Lily, "goofed it"?
What do you mean I goofed it?
What happened?
Oh!
Don't you "But, Lily" me.
All right. I'll tell you
exactly what happened.
This afternoon, a certain party
went to the bank...
with a bankbook showing $680
in the account, hmm?
Mm-hmm.
And a withdrawal slip
made out for $680.
Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
Now, what did
this certain party do?
Did he come home with $680?
No, he did not.
This featherbrained klutz
came home...
with $18,300
that didn't belong to him.
That's what he did.
Now, what would you
have to say to that?
I would say that was
a remarkable coincidence.
Because, you know,
the same thing happened to me.
Herman.
Hmm?
You are the featherbrained klutz
to whom I was referring.
Oh. Oh, l... l... I was?
I mean, you were?
I mean...
Oh. Well, golly, Lily.
You don't have to
put all the blame on me.
L... I mean, your own father
was along with me, you know.
And he's not half as big a...
uh, what... what you said as I am.
And anyway,
when the lady at the bank
gave us all that money,
I couldn't just start
counting it right there,
'cause she might have thought
I didn't trust her.
Then she might have
gotten angry at me,
started yelling and everything.
Well... l-I'm sorry, dear.
I guess it wasn't all your fault.
I don't know how it happened,
but I do know one thing.
You've just got to take that money
back to the bank tomorrow.
I mean, it's... it's only
the fair, adult thing to do.
Isn't it, sweetheart?
I guess so.
Then you're not mad at me anymore?
How could I stay mad
at you, pussycat?
What are you doing?
Uh, uh, I've never seen
this much money before.
Can't I just play with it
till I have to give it back?
Oh, Herman!
18,100.
18,200.
$18,300.
[Chuckles]
Money, money.
[Sighs]
Money.
My good man, I'll take
that black limousine and two of
those red convertibles, please.
Thank you.
[Chuckles]
Money.
[Laughing]
Please, girls,
stop kissing me. Stop.
Just because I gave you
a few diamond necklaces,
doesn't mean you own me.
Zsa Zsa, no.
You'll have to stand in line
like the rest.
I'm rolling in money.
I'm swimming in money.
I'm drowning in money.
Drowning.
All right, drown.
Help! Help!
I'm drowning.
You can't let me drown.
I'm a rich man.
Help!
Are you quite through, Mr. Rockefeller?
Oh, it's you, Lily.
I was dreaming.
[Sighs]
I thought I was a rich man.
Well, you're not.
So will you please send Zsa Zsa home
and let's get some sleep.
Zsa Zsa?
Lily, I know I won't be able to sleep
till that money's back in the bank.
Oh, of course you will.
And you'll take it back in the morning
as soon as the bank is open.
Now good night.
I'm just dead.
[Huffing]
I know I won't be able to sleep
till that money's back in the bank.
To heck with waiting for it to open.
I'll take it back tonight.
Don't touch me.
I'm gonna short-circuit
the burglar alarm system.
[Electricity Crackling]
Grandpa, uh, uh,
are you all right?
Well, just a little lightheaded.
Now, Herman,
I just short-circuited
the main fuse.
Give me this.
Now, go ahead, open the door.
After you, Grandpa.
If I remember correctly,
the vault is someplace over there.
Herman? Herman, where are you?
I'm over here.
What are you doing?
Uh, I just thought I'd fill
my fountain pen.
Fill your fountain pen.
Herman, will you come on.
I found the vault.
[Metal Clanks]
Would you help?
Butterfingers. Here. Hold this.
Look. It's set for
9:00 a.m. In the morning.
Oh.
Maybe it works like
an alarm clock.
What do you mean?
Well, they...
Uh, uh, maybe they
set it from the back.
Uh, uh, what time
shall I set it for?
Ooh.
Look, it... it's almost 3:00.
Set it for 3:00.
All right.
[Whispering]
10:00, 11:00, 12:00,
1:00 and 2:00...
and 3:00.
[Lock Clicks]
[Bell Dings]
[Laughing]
After you, Grandpa.
[Wheezing Laugh]
Uh, Grandpa, I'll feel around
for the light switch.
Good idea.
Ah.
Ah. It's rather pleasant in here.
Reminds me a little
of the catacombs I used to
crawl around in when I was very little.
Well, Herman, uh,
we might as well say good-bye
to our short-lived prosperity.
Uh, good-bye,
short-lived prosperity.
Well, that was easy enough.
Now all we have to do
is go home and...
[Door Closes]
[Locks Clicking, Whirring]
Grandpa, did you hear
a door slam?
Yes, I did hear a door slam.
Was it a back door?
No, it wasn't a back door.
Was it a side door?
No, it wasn't a side door.
What kind of door was it?
[Together]
It was the only door.
Herman!
Herman, we're locked in!
We're trapped, Herman!
We're hermetically sealed
in here, Herman!
These walls are
made of solid steel.
Herman, we may never
get out of here!
Herman, don't you understand?
We may never get out of here.
Well, it'll teach us
a darn good lesson
to be more careful next time.
[Frustrated Groan]
Why?
Marilyn. Marilyn.
Oh, yes, Aunt Lily?
Oh, I hate to disturb you, dear,
but have you seen your Uncle Herman?
He's gone.
Oh, well, maybe
he's in with Grandpa.
No, I've already checked Grandpa's room.
His slab hasn't even been slept on.
Do you suppose they might have
gone on one of their strolls
through the cemetery?
They just might have.
Herman was so worried
about that money...
that he was having trouble
getting to sleep.
I'm afraid I wasn't
very sympathetic.
Oh, I'm sure that's
where they are, Aunt Lily.
And you know if there's one thing
those two really dig,
it's graveyards.
Grandpa, we've just gotta find
a way to get out of here.
Grandpa? Grandpa?
Grandpa? Oh.
Grandpa, we've gotta find a way
to get out of here.
You're right.
Now, we've just got to keep looking.
And that way we might just
be able to...
Herman, look.
"For emergency use only. '"
Grandpa, look.
A telephone.
I'll just call the police department,
tell them we're locked in,
they'll come get us
and we'll be out in no time.
Operator, get me
the police department.
[Woman]
Which precinct, please?
Precinct?
Uh, Mockingbird Heights Precinct.
That's a local number.
You may dial it direct, sir.
Yes, but you see,
I don't have the number.
Local numbers are listed
in your directory.
But, miss,
there is no directory here.
You see, I'm locked in a v...
I'll connect you with Information.
She's getting me Information.
Herman, Information? Wha...
Information, could I have the number
of the Mockingbird Heights
Police Department, please?
[Woman]
That number is 177-9771.
[Mumbling Number]
Thank you, miss.
177-9771.
Right.
Write that down, Grandpa.
I will.
I don't seem to have anything
to write it with.
Herman, give me your pen.
177-9771.
17...
It's empty.
You wouldn't let me fill it.
Ooh! Fill it...
We'll just have to
remember it. Here.
177-9771.
Right.
They'll want to know where we are.
What's the address of this bank?
I think it's 40691 st Street.
40691 st Street.
I'll just keep that in my head.
You got it?
I got it. 40691 st Street.
And the telephone number
is 177-9771.
Right.
And, Herman,
when you get the police,
they'll be here in five or 10 minutes.
If they go like 60,
we'll have seven or eight of them
down here in 20 winks.
And it'll be one, two,
button my shoe,
three, four,
and they'll open the door!
Oh!
Herman. Herman,
what are you waiting for?
Dial the number.
You made me forget it.
"Forget it." Oh, this is ridiculous.
Herman, give me that thing.
[Rotary Dials]
"One, two, buckle my shoe."
Listen, lady,
this is an emergency.
My friend and I are here,
and we're locked in a bank vault together,
and the walls are two feet thick,
and we're... we're running out of air.
If you don't get somebody down here
immediately, we'll both be dead.
Listen, lady. Please, do something.
[Woman]
I'd love to help you, sir,
but this is a recording.
It's a recording.
Grandpa, what did you push?
The light went on.
"Push to summon police."
[Laughs]
Maybe we'll be
rescued after all.
[Wheezing Laugh]
Oh, Herman, before we know it,
there'll be someone
on the other side of the door
trying to get in.
You know, Fingers,
we're really throwing the cops off...
in hitting this place at night
instead of in the daytime.
Sure, Scotty,
and I always felt like a goon
wearing that Halloween mask.
I thought it was
really becoming to you.
There's the vault. Come on.
Hey. Hey.
What a... What a break.
What a break.
Someone, uh, disconnecting
the... the burglar alarm.
And that front door's
the easiest lock
I ever picked.
Yeah. This bank
is sure askin' for it.
Listen, we gotta blow this vault,
get the loot and scram out of here.
Oh, yeah.
Come on.
Come on. Start your drill.
I'll hold the flashlight.
Come on. Let's get goin'.
All right. Let her rip.
[Drill Whirring]
Grandpa, listen.
Somebody's working on the door.
It sounds like a big drill.
We're being rescued.
[Laughing]
A drill?
Who wants to be rescued
by a dentist?
Okay, Scotty,
there she is.
Are you sure this job's
gonna be worth it?
Fingers, when we blow this door off,
you just ain't gonna believe
what's inside.
Light it.
Grandpa, it got quiet
out there.
You don't suppose
they've given up?
[Laughs]
Don't be ridiculous, Herman.
They must have stopped
to have a cigarette or something.
I'm sure we'll be hearing a noise
any minute now.
[Explosion]
Hi!
Herman, these are the ones
who did it.
Oh, Grandpa,
I feel so good,
I'm gonna give 'em a big hug.
[Chuckling]
I think we better get out of here
before somebody shows up.
They don't look like police to me.
[Mouthing Words]
Read some more
about the bank robbers, Grandpa.
Well, "Scotty Malone
and Fingers Dusick...
"upon being revived by police
at the scene of the attempted robbery...
"blamed their capture
on two unidentified citizens...
who appeared from nowhere
and rendered them unconscious."
Oh, how brave of you, Herman.
"Now, these are thought to be
the same persons...
who summoned the police
on the bank's alarm system."
And it says a reward is waiting
if the two men come forward.
Are you gonna claim it, Herman?
Oh, I don't really think so, Lily.
It would mean interviews
and photographs,
and you know how shy I am
about having my picture taken.