[ Car Horn Honks ]
Ooh, my goodness!
There's your carpool.
You'd really better hurry.
Yes, dear.
[ Laughing ]
Just like the Old Country.
Does my heart good
to see a man wolf his food.
Well, good-bye, everybody.
[ Together]
Bye.
Good-bye, Lily.
Will you be home
from the parlor early, dear?
Oh. Well, today we're having
our annual office party.
Oh. Well, then be careful.
Uh, those office parties
can get a little wild.
Oh, y-you don't have to
worry about me, dear.
I'm no watercooler Casanova.
As a matter of fact,
I'm so square,
I understand some
of the secretaries are starting
to refer to me...
as ""Herman the Cube.''
Well, come home
as soon as you can.
Eh, I'll be home
at least by 6:30.
Uh, good-bye, all.
[ Together]
Bye.
You think Munster's wife
will let him stay
for the office party tonight?
We told him
it would be over by 6:30--
that way she'll let him go.
Yeah, but it won't really
get going till 9:00.
Old Herman will be lucky
if he gets home by midnight.
Shh. Here he comes.
Hey, Mom, when's Dad
coming home from work?
He wasn't here
for supper or anything.
Well, you see, Eddie,
there are times...
when the social requirements
of his job,
and the morale
of his fellow employees,
require your father's presence
after closing time.
Hmm. Another
office party, huh?
Well, something like that.
Now, don't you think you'd better
run along to bed?
Okay.
Have you done everything?
Have you put away your toys
and brushed your fangs?
Mm-hmm.
All right. That's fine, Eddie.
Good night.
Don't forget Woof-Woof.
Oh, of course.
Good night, Grandpa.
Hmm.
Good night, Eddie.
Good night, Woof-Woof.
Good night.
Hey, Mom, can Spot sleep
in my room tonight?
All right, Eddie,
but be careful.
He has a slight cold, and I don't
want him to start sneezing
and set fire to the drapes.
Good night.
Come on, Spot!
You get to sleep
with me tonight.
[ Growls ]
Good boy, Spot.
Ah, there's nothing more touching
than a boy and his pet.
[ Footsteps Thudding ]
[ Squawks ]
9:00 and all's well.
Correction.
The bum ain't home yet.
Smart aleck.
Oh, I had no idea
it was so late.
Now I'm really angry
with Herman.
I'm going to call him up again
and tell him off.
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Crowd ]
? Camptown ladies sing this song?
?Doo-dah?
Hello?
This is Lily.
What do you mean, ""Lily who''?
This is your wife!
Oh, Lily! I'm, uh,
I'm glad you called, dear.
? Oh, doo-dah day?
Do you know the lyrics
to the second chorus
of""Shortenin' Bread''?
? Doo-dah, doo-dah ?
?Doo-dah, doo-dah?
Herman Munster!
I have had enough of this!
You come right home this--
? Oh, doo-dah day?
Now what was that, Lily?
[ Woman ]
Come on back, Hermie baby.!
Eh, coming, Miss Haversham.
- Oh, what was that, dear?
- [ Grunts ]
Lily?
??[ Continues ]
Lily!
Guess we were cut off.
??[ Ends ]
Say, do you fellas know
""Moonlight on the Ganges''?
Grandpa, I'm not gonna
wait around here any longer.
If that cornball Caruso
calls back,
you tell him
I've gone to bed!
Oh, I'm so mad
I could chew nails!
Eh, Lily, be my guest.
Thank you.
[ Crunching ]
[ Herman ]
?Doo-dah, doo-dah?
[ Chuckling ]
? Camptown races
doo-dah-doo ?
? Doo-doo, doo-doo
doo-dah, doo ??
Grandpa?
Grandpa!
Oh, Herman, it's you.
Hi, Grandpa.
I guess I must have dozed off...
while I was hanging around
waiting for you.
Where's Lily?
Oh, she's upstairs
waiting for you.
Oh, good. I had such
a good time at the party.
I'm gonna go upstairs
and tell her all about it.
[ Chuckles ]
You know,
let her in on the fun.
[ Chuckles ]
Whoopee!
[ Laughing ]
Well, there he goes.
In the mood she's in,
she's liable to tear him apart.
Well, lucky I'm good
at jigsaw puzzles.
I'd better get upstairs
and hit the slab
before the trouble starts.
?? [ Humming ""Camptown Races'' ]
Hmm. That's funny.
The door must be stuck.
Lily?
? Herman's come back
home to stay?
? Doo-dah, doo-dah ?
[ Laughs ]
Lily?
I guess she's not in there.
She's in there, all right.
Lily?
Baby.
I-It's Hermie.
Now-- O-O-Open the door
like a good little wifey.
Lily. No more teasing.
Pussycat wanna go sleepy-bye.
Well, pussycat can
just go sleepy-bye...
on the living room couch!
[ Snoring ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Laughing ]
E-Eh, Lily, stop it.
N-No matter what you do,
I'm not coming upstairs.
Lily! Lily!
[ Growls ]
Oh.
[ Growling ]
Cute kitty.
[ Soft Tapping ]
What's that?
It's that leaky faucet
in the kitchen. Hmm.
I'll just ignore it.
[ Tapping Continues ]
[ Groaning ]
I'll shut it off.
[ Crashes ]
What?
I'd better light a match.
John Wayne never
has that trouble.
[ Tapping Continues ]
[ Creaks ]
[ Groans ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Gasps, Screams ]
[ Squeaking ]
[ Yelling ]
Help! Help! Help!
Help! Oh, good heavens!
Help! Help!
Help.! Help.! Help.!
Help.! Help.!
Pop, what happened?
Help.!
H-Herman, Herman,
wh-what's the matter?
A mouse!
There was a big,
mean-looking mouse,
and he was after me.
Herman, will you come down
from there? Come down!
He made a face at me--
and he showed his teeth
and everything.
Herman, look,
he's all gone.
Will you please
go to sleep and don't
worry about anything?
Don't be scared, Pop.
Me and Grandpa will be
right upstairs.
That's right, son.
Now-Now, get along.
Get along to bed.
[ Groans ]
Come on, Eddie.
[ Screams ]
[ Grandpa ]
Good night.
Oh, good night.
Oh, where is everybody?
Everybody's had breakfast
and gone off to school.
Oh.
Grandpa, would you
mind telling me...
why this person
is sitting at my table?
I'm waiting
for breakfast.
Would you tell this person
that everybody who was
going to get breakfast...
already had breakfast.
Lily, I'm hungry!
Eh, as husband, father...
and head of the household,
I demand breakfast!
What's this?
Prune pits.
Three of them.
One for the father,
one for the husband...
and one for
the head of the house.
Eh--
Grandpa,
what am I going to do?
I can't spend the rest
of my married life
sleeping on the couch...
and eating prune pits.
Herman, if you give in now,
she'll have the upper hand forever.
[ Cackles ]
But, if you hold out,
she'll come around.
That's the way
to handle women! Mmm.
[ Crunching ]
What are you doing?
Well,just in case
she doesn't come around,
I'm gonna get used
to eating prune pits.
Grandpa,
this is the fourth night
in a row I've slept down here!
When is Lily
gonna give in?
Herman, I hate to say it,
but I think we're licked.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm afraid you just don't have
the personality and warmth
you used to have.
In other words, my boy,
in that great furnace
known as romance,
your pilot light
has gone out.
Grandpa, you certainly have
a way with words.
Thank you.
But how am I gonna
turn up the burner?
Wait. I think
I have the answer.
Here.
Read this.
""Is your marriage shaky?
""Headed for the rocks?
""See Dr. Harvey Baxter, M.C.,
Marriage Counselor.
Broken hearts made whole.''
Ah, Grandpa.
Me go to a marriage counselor?
[ Chuckles ]
Marilyn, me go
to a marriage counselor?
Yes. Well, you and Uncle Herman
are getting farther apart every day.
And neither of you
are going to give in.
I think it's the only solution.
[ Scoffs ]
I wouldn't know who to go to.
Well, Aunt Lily, I read an ad
in the paper this morning,
and so I called and I made
an appointment for you
for tomorrow.
The man's name
is Dr. Harvey Baxter.
All right, I'll try...
on one condition--
that your Uncle Herman
never knows.
Now, as I was saying,
my name is Mrs. Mu--
No names, please.
I find that people
are less inhibited
if they remain anonymous.
Now then,
what is your problem?
Well, to begin with, Doctor,
I'm married.
Don't be ashamed of it.
Virtually every person
who's walked through that door...
has made
the same mistake.
Now, tell me something
about your background.
- For instance, where were you born?
- Transylvania.
My father is a count.
And your husband?
No count.
Uh, bitterness
is not the answer.
I meant, where was he born?
Oh, my husband
was made, Doctor, not born.
Oh, oh, yes, of course.
That's, that's fine.
Every woman should think
her husband is a self-made man.
Oh, he had help.
Now, madam, tell me,
is there another woman?
No, the doctor quit after Herman.
Well, e-exactly what is
the cause of your domestic trouble?
Well, it all started
down at his place
of employment.
Ah, that is a familiar complaint.
The wife neglected for the job.
I suppose he just
buries himself in his work.
Oh, no, no. Not Herman.
Although there have been
a few close calls.
You see, Doctor,
the trouble started...
when they had this party
down at the office.
He didn't get home
until after 1 2:00.
Aha! This is
an old story to me.
Ah, the gay playboy husband.
But, fortunately,
there is an easy solution.
You must go home
and apologize immediately.
Me, apologize?
I'm not the one who came home
in the middle of the night
and sang ""doo-dah, doo-dah''...
through the keyhole.
If you take the first step,
it will put the burden
squarely on his shoulders,
and he will realize
what a loving, forgiving wife you are.
Well, I'll try it.
But, remember,
you must assume
the role of peacemaker...
and be the first
to forgive and forget.
Uh, Doctor,
I think your secretary's
taking a sunbath.
Uh, she jumped out the window
and ran up the fire escape
to the roof.
Good heavens, man,
what happened to you?
Well, you see, my wife
and I have had a fight.
You-- You should have
defended yourself, man.
No one should stand still
and take a beating like that.
Nobody hit me.
You mean there's been
no physical violence?
No, Doctor. My problems
are purely emotional.
Yes. Yes, that's obvious.
Sit down.
Oh, thank you.
Now, uh, let's begin
at the beginning.
Well, my wife has locked me
out of the bedroom...
and won't let me in.
Naturally. But has she
done anything unusual?
U-Uh, no, you don't
understand, Doctor.
She's not only locked me out
of the bedroom,
she won't feed me.
Eh, she won't even
speak to me.
What was the cause
of the quarrel?
Oh. Well, a few evenings ago...
I stayed out rather late...
for business reasons.
Uh, when I got home,
my wife was disturbed.
She rejected me...
and made me sleep
downstairs on the couch.
And, Doctor,
for the last four days,
the only thing I've had
my arms around...
is a Woof-Woof.
My advice to you is this--
that you go home at once
and apologize.
- Apologize?
- Exactly.
At any cost you must be the one
to take the first step toward reconciliation.
Do not allow your wife...
to assume
the role of peacemaker.
Lily, I want to talk to you.
And I want to talk
to you too, darling.
There's something
I want to tell you, dear.
Oh, I'll be glad to listen,
but I want to tell you
something first.
Uh, Lily, dear,
if you don't mind,
could I tell you what I want
to tell you before you tell me
what you want to tell me?
Eh-Eh, no, dear.
You let me go first,
because what I have to say
will save our marriage.
Uh, Lily, if anyone's gonna
save our marriage,
I'm gonna save our marriage.
Oh, no you're not.
Lily,
all I'm trying to do
is say I'm sorry and apologize.
You apologize?
B-But you can't apologize to me...
before I have a chance
to apologize to you.
Lily, all I want to be
is the peacemaker.
You the peacemaker?
Oh, you big dummy!
I'm going to be the peacemaker,
so get that through your thick head!
Lily, will you pipe down
while I'm trying to be sweet
and apologize?
Ooh. That does it!
I'm not gonna sit around here
a-and be apologized to...
by a poor insensitive oaf!.
Lily! Lily!
Lily!
I-I'm sleeping
in our bed tonight.
I am! I am! I am!
[ Whimpers ]
Fiddlesticks!
Oh.
Thank you, son.
Oh, Grandpa, why do you
keep fooling around with that...
when we have such
a serious problem
on our hands?
[ Chuckles ]
Because, my dear, this
is going to solve the problem.
This is a formula
for instant measles.
Wait a minute.
Who's gonna have the measles?
You are.
But they're synthetic.
No fever. No scratching.
Just two happy parents reunited.
? Dee-da, da-da, la-da ??
Okay, Eddie, there you go.
You mean I have
to drink this stuff?
Drink it?
[ Chuckles ]
What do you mean, drink it?
?? [ Humming ]
- Do you think that'll work?
- Certainly.
When Herman and Lily
think their little boy is sick,
they'll be so worried
it'll bring them back together.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, Grandpa,
you're a psychologist.
No, I'm not. It's a trick
I learned from watching
old Shirley Temple movies.
Herman!
Herman, come quickly!
It's Eddie!
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
Coming, dear.! Coming.!
Lily! Lily! Lily!
Lily, what is it!?
Oh, I brought him in here, Herman.
Look!
Now, Lily, dear, don't panic.
Herman's here.
We'll think
of something... together.
Oh, but look at his face.
[ Crashes ]
Ooh. Oh, Herman.
Oh, you're so kind and sweet
and precious and adorable.
And-And sometimes
you're a goofball,
but I love you.
Oh, Lily,
say that again.
U-Uh, um, but this time, dear,
leave out ""goofball.''
It is wonderful--
one minute alone
with Grandpa...
and his measles disappeared.
Not one single mark
on that sweet little face.
Oh, it's miraculous.
No, Lily,
I understand it perfectly.
Eddie's measles
were psychosomatic--
the result of worrying
about us quarreling.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, he'll never have to
worry about that again,
will he, pussycat?
Never! No more
office parties for me.
From now on, I'm having
all my fun right here at home!
[ Laughs ]
?? [ Organ ]
? Camptown ladies sing this song ?
? Doo-dah, doo-dah ?
? Camptown racetrack
five miles long ?
? Oh, doo-dah day?
? Gwine to run all night ?
? Gwine to run all day?
? Bet my money on
a bobtail nag ?
? Somebody bet on the bay??