Thanks for the lift, Charlie.
Pick me up around 9:00
tomorrow morning.
Lily, pussycat is home.
Good evening, dear.
I see the carpool
dropped you off again.
Yes, and it was quite
restful riding in the back.
Oh! Mail, dear?
No, but it's something
I'm very upset about.
I was putting up
some new cobwebs
in Marilyn's room,
and I, um, accidentally found this
hidden in her bureau drawer.
Oh, a love letter.
[Laughs]
Let's read it.
Herman,
it's not a love letter.
It's an announcement
of a parents' night
at Marilyn's school.
It's next Saturday night
and she hasn't even asked us yet.
I have a feeling she doesn't
want us to be seen at her school
for some strange reason.
And I think we ought to get
to the bottom of this at supper.
Well, it may not be
that serious, Lily.
L-It may just have
slipped her mind.
Things are always
popping out of my head.
Yes, but with you,
we can always put them back in.
Now remember, Herman,
we have to find out why Marilyn
hasn't mentioned parents' night
at school.
But we have to be
very subtle about it.
Be very subtle. I see.
How do we do that?
Well, we lead up
to it gradually.
First I'll bring up
the subject of cars.
Cars.
That'll lead to driving.
Driving.
And then I'll bring up
the subject of driving to school.
Driving to school. Of course.
And that'll lead up to...
[Together]
Parents' night.
Gotcha.
[Door Opens]
Oh, my! Everything looks
so delicious, Lily.
Oh, thank you,
Grandpa.
[Clears Throat]
Uh, Marilyn, how do you feel
about the new cars?
New cars?
Well, I think that...
And how come you didn't
ask us to parents' night at school?
Parents'night? Well,
where did you hear about that?
Well... Well, dear,
I was dusting your room,
and I just happened
to come across the invitation.
It's, uh, next Saturday night,
isn't it?
Yes, Marilyn.
Don't try to hide anything.
You know, in this family
nothing ever stays buried.
The reason I didn't mention it
was because...
Well, because of you,
Uncle Herman.
Me? Well, why wouldn't you
want me, of all people,
to go to parents' night?
Well, I just didn't think
you'd care for it.
It's going to be sort of
a dinner dance.
Oh. [Chuckles]
Dancing.
Why didn't you say so?
Dancing has never been
one of my strong points.
I guess you could say
I have two left feet.
Well, that's what happens
when they put someone
together in the dark.
Herman,
I think we should go.
I mean, at your age,
it's high time you took up dancing.
Lily, you know I hate dancing.
I've always hated to dance.
I'm not going through with it.
I am not going down there
at the risk of making a fool out of myself.
I am not going dancing!
And one, two, three.
One, two, three.
One, two, three. One...
Herman. Herman, relax.
You're so stiff.
Yeah, Herman, let everything go.
Well, I'll-I'll try,
but the last time I let everything go,
some of it didn't come back.
One, two, three.
One, two...
I think I'm getting the knack of it.
[Laughs]
Timber!
Herman...
[Harp Thrums]
You know something, Lily,
I just got a new respect
for Lawrence Welk.
Marilyn, Eddie!
What happened?
Come and help
your Uncle Herman.
Careful.
[Exhales]
Listen, Lily.
They're playing our song.
Ah!
If that Herman wants to dance,
I'll mix him something
that'll make him dance.
Ho, ho! Now, let me see.
Ah, yes, now I know.
A little potassium.
?? [Humming]
A pinch of chlorophyll.
Two fingers of Geritol.
A dash of bitters.
And now for the secret ingredient!
A pair of Fred Astaire's
dancing shoes.
[Shoes Tapping, Shuffling]
Go, Fred, go.
Grandpa?
Grandpa, are you
making lasagna again?
You're smelling up the whole house.
No, as a matter of fact, I'm whipping up
a batch of my secret dancing potion.
This will make you
a wonderful dancer.
No, sir. I'm not drinking
anything you mix up.
Okay. Go to
the parents' night dance.
Disgrace poor Marilyn.
Make a fool of yourself.
I'm not gonna
disgrace anybody.
Listen to this.
I found an ad in the newspaper,
and they're gonna make me...
an accomplished ballroom dancer
in three easy lessons.
Listen:
"Happyland Ballroom.
"Fox-trot, tango, samba, watusi.
All the latest steps.
"Gain poise, popularity.
Make friends.
Free trial lesson.
Private and group rates. '"
Herman, listen to me.
There are plenty
of good dancing schools,
but you gotta watch out
for the shysters.
Shysters?
Uh, but look what it says...
"Let us bring out the inner you
at our low monthly rates."
And it's signed,
"Happy Havemeyer,
Doctor ofTerpsichore."
Okay. If that's
what you want to do.
That's exactly what I want to do.
I'm going to go down there
and sign up first thing in the morning.
Hm.
Hm!
All right, fine.
Yes, that'll be okay.
Bye-bye.
Miss Valentine,
if you would.
since you're a new instructor
here at Happyland, I'd like to
acquaint you with our policy.
Most of our clients are older people,
misfits, widowers,
people searching for friendship.
Some are rather bewildered,
and they come to us looking for guidance.
We have a definite approach
to these folks.
- What's that, Doctor?
- We take 'em for all they've got.
Uncle Herman left early,
didn't he?
Yes, the sweet thing went downtown
to take dancing lessons.
He's so anxious
to make a good impression
at the parents' night dance.
I'm surprised that he never learned
to dance when he was younger.
Well, when other young men
were going to parties and dances,
I'm afraid he was always tied up
in the laboratory.
You know, they have
women teachers down
at those dancing schools.
I just hope one of them
doesn't fall in love with
your Uncle Herman's gentle charms.
[Screams]
Doctor Havemeyer.!
Calm down, Miss Valentine.
What happened?
Well, l-I know you said
there'd be a lot of weirdos
and misfits around here,
but you should've seen
what just walked in
and wanted to take dancing lessons.
You gotta see him!
Now, now. There's no need
for me to see him.
Didn't I tell you
to expect all kinds?
Now, you get back in there,
turn on the charm.
Flatter him. Tell him
how great a dancer he is.
And then when you got him hooked,
get him to sign our 10-year contract.
[Chuckles]
Well, I'll try.
It's times like this I wish I'd stayed
with the Roller Derby.
Oh, there you are, miss.
Was there some emergency?
You left here so fast,
I thought the place was on fire.
[Laughs]
No such luck.
Well, shall we start?
Alrighty.
?? [Jazz]
Uh, excuse me.
Yeah, that's better.
Now, the first thing you have to do
is put your arm around me.
Oh, uh...
I saw Robert Montgomery
do that once.
Ready?
Ready.
And... one...
And... one and two
and one and two.
And three and four.
Now one and two
and three and four...
and one and two
and three and four.
Tell me, Mr. Munster,
have you ever danced professionally?
Professionally?
Heavens no!
I would have
never known.
Really?
[Laughs]
[Herman]
Yoo-hoo, Lily. I'm home.
Oh, welcome home, dear.
Well, how did my sweetheart
make out at dancing class?
How did I make out?
I made out just beautifully, Lily.
Miss Valentine said
after just one lesson,
I was a natural born dancer.
She's never seen such a talent.
Oh, that's wonderful!
I just know that when I
dance with you at the ball,
every eye in the room
will be on us.
And, Lily, Miss Valentine
said that Dr. Havemeyer...
might even make me a teacher
after a few more lessons.
A teacher!
And, Lily, I was reading today
in a fan magazine...
You know, that's the way
Gene Kelly started out...
as a dancing teacher.
Then he starred in Pal Joey,
then he was a big smash
in For Me and My Gal,
and then there was
Gene's biggest hit,
Singing in the Rain.
? I'm singing in the rain
just singing in the rain?
? What a glorious feeling
I'm happy again?
? I'm laughing at clouds?
[Laughs]
? So dark up above?
? The sun's in my heart
and I'm ready for love??
[Laughs]
[Harp Thrums]
Marilyn, Grandpa.
Come on.
Oh, boy. He's got
his head in the harp again.
[Caws]
What a crack-up.!
Please, watch the face.
I'm gonna be a star.
?? [Jazz]
[Laughing]
?? [Ends]
Mr. Munster!
What is it?
The music has stopped.
Don't bring me back now.
I'm too far out!
Oh, Mr. Mun...
Man, it's wig city!
Please, Mr. Munster. Please.
Your lesson is over
for this evening.
However, Dr. Havemeyer
would like you to sign up
for a special course.
It's inexpensive and the lessons
extend over a 10-year period.
Really?
Am I that good?
Oh, yes. You're marvelous!
Wheeee!
Sit down right here,
and I'll get you the papers to sign.
[Breathing Heavily]
Catch your breath.
They're, um...
They're all stapled together,
so you don't have to bother
to read the fine print.
Thank you.
That's very thoughtful of you.
Hey, Mom, can I take Spot
to school with me today?
Not today, Eddie.
Spot's being punished.
He got out last night and ate
all the neighbor's trash cans.
Morning, all.
Hi.
Morning, Lily.
Good morning, dear.
Morning, Herman.
Uh, how's Gene Kelly this morning?
Couldn't be better.
The dancing school is signing me up
to a 10-year contract.
Marilyn, you're gonna be
very proud of your Uncle Herman
at the dance Saturday night.
Your lunch pail's
all packed, dear.
And here's your breakfast.
Oh, thank you.
[Car Horn Honks]
Oh, there's the carpool.
I'd better run.
Wrong? It's this contract
that Herman signed
with the dancing school.
He signed a 10-year contract
for 1,500 lessons...
at 750 a lesson!
Why, that's...
11,250.
Thank you, Eddie.
And that's only the beginning.
There's more?
More?
A life insurance policy
naming the school as benefiiciary.
In case of default,
a garnishee on Herman's salary.
A lien on his home.
An attachment on his automobile.
And in case of any legal action,
a waiver of all his rights
as an American citizen.
What are we going to do, Grandpa?
Well, we just can't let him
know he's been taken.
Poor dear is so sensitive,
he's liable to go right into his shell.
His shell? What did you marry,
a man or a lobster?
Oh, Grandpa. We'll just have to
think of some other way.
Oh, Lily. Forget it.
Lily, I got it. I got it.
I'll take care of it.
Now, the first thing I'll do,
I'll turn that whole school
into a swamp.
Then I'll turn the owner into a frog.
Then I'll turn all the other teachers
into lizards.
I'll turn myself Into an alligator.
A hungry alligator.
Then I'll start eatin' my way...
Oh, stop it, Father.
This is no time to be
thinking of your pleasures.
Aw, gee, Mom. You never let Grandpa
have any fun anymore.
Never you mind, Eddie.
We Munsters
are law-abiding citizens,
and we're going to call
the police right now.
Well, you better hurry. Herman's
got another lesson tonight.
Right. I gotcha.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Miss Valentine,
I just got an inside tip
that the cops are going to
run an investigation on us.
Look, what they usually do is
they get an investigator
to pose as a student.
Some clod who acts like he can't
get out of his own way.
And when he gets the evidence on us...
Wham! Out come the handcuffs.
[Herman]
Yoo-hoo.! Uh, Miss Valentine?
Twinkletoes is here!
I'll be right there.!
If you think that the...
Look, Dr. Havemeyer.
Speaking of clods who
can't get out of their own way,
I think the police
are onto us already.
- What do you mean?
- You know that student we signed up
to the 10-year contract yesterday?
I didn't think he was for real
from the beginning.
Yeah? I'd better
have a look at him.
?? [Jazz]
Wow.
That's the weirdest disguise
I've ever seen.
The cops are really
reaching this time.
He looks like a cross between
Little Abner and Ramses II.
What do we do now, Doctor?
We take desperate measures.
We turn honest.
We tell him after
analyzing his dancing,
we find out that he
has absolutely no talent,
and we're refunding his money.
But, Dr. Havemeyer,
M-M-Miss Valentine,
y-you must be kidding me.
I'm afraid not, Mr. Munster.
You mean I won't
be a dancing teacher?
No. Upon analysis, we find your dancing
to be crude and awkward.
And your coordination is atrocious.
You have absolutely no sense of rhythm.
But I wanna be a teacher,
and maybe get to Broadway,
and then get to Hollywood,
and become a big dancing star
like Gene Kelly.
And get to meet people like
Kirk Douglas and Nick Adams
and all those big shots.
I'm sorry. It is our decision
to return your money,
tear up your contract
and discontinue your lessons.
But you can't do that.
I mean, I promised to go
to parents' night with my niece...
and do the fox-trot
and the bunny hop.
Well, now I'll just look
silly and stupid.
I don't wanna look
stupid and silly.
I don't want to. I don't want to.
I don't want to!
I don't want to! I don't want to!
I don't want to.! I don't want to.!
[Record Crashes]
What do you think, Doctor?
I think it's the greatest performance
by a policeman since Pat O'Brien.
I told my date that
we'd meet him at the dance.
Well, that's a good idea, Marilyn.
The last time a young man
came to our house to pick you up,
he had some sort of an attack
right on our front porch.
Oh, I wonder if Uncle Herman
has the car out yet.
Why, Herman, you're not
even dressed yet.
Yes, Uncle Herman.
And we're due there now.
I'm sorry, girls.
I'm not going.
Not going? But we've been
looking forward to this all week,
and you took
all those dancing lessons.
And you brought that tuxedo home
from the parlor and everything.
Well, Herman has
something to tell you about
the dancing school.
Well, the truth is that last night,
they tore up my 10-year contract,
gave me back the money
and told me to get lost.
Oh, well, that was
just a phony school.
W-Well, that doesn't matter.
W-What does matter is...
they showed me that I must
face the truth about myself.
And I realize that when you
add it up on the scoreboard of life,
Herman Munster is just
a big, awkward clod.
Oh, darling,
you are not at all.
Well, uh, be that as it may,
l-I want you to go to the dance, Lily,
and you, Marilyn,
and enjoy yourselves...
amidst the lights
and the music and the gaiety.
But, pussycat...
No, no. No, no.
Lily, I want you to go.
L-I insist.
And, uh, if, during the evening,
some attractive gentlemen...
comes up to you
and asks you to dance,
I want you to feel free to accept.
And, uh, while you're dancing,
and he's holding you tight,
I don't want you
to give one moment's thought...
to your faithful husband
sitting here alone...
with his shriveled-up
old father-in-law.
Herman, you're all heart.
Oh, but, Uncle Herman...
No, no. Go... out the door
and don't look back.
Well, all right, Herman,
if you insist.
Come on, Marilyn.
[Door Opens, Closes]
You know, shrivel...
l-I mean, Grandpa...
it gives me a good feeling inside
knowing I did the right thing.
[Caws]
What a cornball.!
[Lily]
Owwww.!
[Marilyn]
Grandpa, Herman.
Aunt Lily fell on
the front porch.
What happened?
Is she all right?
Well, I think she sprained her ankle.
Oooh.! Oooh. Oooh.
Just help me
to the sofa, Herman.
I don't know
how it happened.
Grandpa, wasn't that
noble of Aunt Lily?
You mean about her
not making a fuss
about her ankle?
Oh, no. Because she pretended...
that she sprained her ankle
so she could stay home
with Uncle Herman.
Oh, boy!
This family's come a long way
from Transylvania...
when we used to pound stakes
into each other.
Now, Eddie, watch this.
Just watch this.
Herman, what are you and Eddie
doing out here
in all this bright sunlight?
Daddy's practicin' baseball.
That's right, Lily.
There's a father and son
baseball game at Eddie's school,
and I'm gonna be ready.
I'm not gonna make a fool
of myself the way I did last week
at Marilyn's dance.
Well, you be careful now, Herman.
Lily, please.
This is my game.
Just watch this.
[Laughs]
Should I bring him
in the house, Mom?
No, Eddie, just leave him there.
The carpool will be by
in 10 minutes to pick him up.