[Pounding]
Good day, madam.
Is your husband home?
Uh, I'm afraid he's not, sir.
Oh. [Chuckles]
Good!
Oh! [Laughing]
Herman!
You're so cute.
You just give me vulture-bumps all over.
L... I do have a certain built-in charm.
Lily, dear, was there any mail today?
No, but the express company
delivered a box from the Old Country.
Oh.
I had them put it in here.
Oh, let's see who it's from.
Eh, it's Uncle Gilbert!
We'll-We'll have you out in a jiffy,
Uncle Gilbert.
You're just in time for dinner.
No, no, Herman. It's not Uncle Gilbert.
It's from Uncle Gilbert.
Oh, eh, sorry. A natural mistake.
I don't know what's in it, but he sent a letter
asking us to keep it for him until he gets here.
He's coming over on a visit
in two or three days.
Oh!
Hey, Pop. I've been waiting
for you to get home.
You can open the crate with
my genuine Transylvanian Boy Scout hatchet.
Thank you, son.
[Shrieks]
Ah! Gold coins. Hundreds of them!
[Eddie]
Yippee.!
But Uncle Gilbert isn't a rich man.
Where in the world would he get
thousands of dollars out of the blue?
Well, Uncle Gilbert used to be a politician.
Maybe Transylvania was declared
an unfriendly nation, and our government
automatically sent them foreign aid.
[Chuckling]
And here's your receipt,
Mrs. Munster.
When we learned you had
such a big deposit, we were happy
to send along our armored car.
I see it came to a hundred
and eighty thousand dollars.
You know, those coins
are pure gold and very rare.
They appear to be Spanish doubloons.
Well, you've been very helpful,
Mr. Benson.
It would be a nuisance
to have all that loose change
kicking about the house.
[Chuckles]
Yeah. Yes.
Everything taken care of,
Aunt Lily?
Oh. This very efficient young man
has been very, very helpful.
Oh, I guess you two haven't met.
Mr. Benson, this is my niece, Marilyn.
Uh, well... [Chuckles]
I'm very glad to meet you, Miss Alan.
My first name is Benson,
but you can call me Marilyn.
Oh, I'm sorry.
A hundred and eighty thousand pardons.
What I mean to say is,
l... I sure am delighted to meet ya.
Uh, well, bye.
Oh. Good evening, Grandpa, Lily.
Uh, sorry I had to work late,
dear, and eat downtown,
but before I left the parlor,
I had to lay out some work
for tomorrow.
That's all right, Herman,
but keep your voice down.
Hm? Keep my voice down?
What are you doing sitting
here in the kitchen?
Don't tell me Spot ate
the living room furniture again!
No, don't, no.
We're sitting here because
Marilyn is sitting in the living room
with a young man.
That new assistant manager
the bank sent over?
He fell for her
like a ton of headstones.
Plain, old, drab Marilyn?
Yes, Herman.
It must be either love or astigmatism.
Lily and I are trying to make sure
he doesn't get away.
Pretty soon, I'm going to sneak out
and bolt the front door.
I'm going out now and see
if they're sitting close together.
[Laughs]
Lily.
Grandpa. I do not believe we should
try to push Marilyn's romance along.
We should let it take its own course.
But, Herman...
Uh, Grandpa. If Marilyn's clock
of romance has begun to tick,
it does not behoove us
to overwind her mainspring.
And the minute I saw you this morning,
I wanted to know you better.
Did you want something,
Aunt Lily?
I hate to disturb you two,
but could I borrow that pillow?
This one, Mrs. Munster?
Yes.
I was making some chicken soup,
and I ran out of feathers.
Hmm. These'll do nicely.
Yeah. Sure.
Oh, Mr. Benson,
uh, why don't you sit over here...
on the sofa next to Marilyn?
[Chuckles]
It's much more comfy.
Yes. Uh, thank you.
She makes chicken soup
with feathers?
Doesn't everyone?
How's everything going?
I borrowed the pillow out of his chair,
so he has to sit on the sofa next to Marilyn.
Good!
Listen, you two.
I am against promoting romance.
It will lead to no good.
We don't want it to lead to any good.
We want it to lead to marriage.
Grandpa. What are you...
What are you doing?
I've got Eddie stashed away
in the dungeon. Ha-ha!
It's part of my master plan.
[Buzzing]
Come in, Eddie.
This is Grandpa. Over.
Well, now, isn't this cozy?
You know, Marilyn,
it's been a long time
since I've met a girl like you,
especially one whose home is so...
[Gasps]
[Creaking]
Hey, hey.!
Alan, what's the matter?
Oh, there's something
coming up out of the floor,
and it's got fangs!
Oh, that's just my little cousin, Eddie.
What is it, Eddie?
Sorry to bother you two,
but one of the lightbulbs
went out down in the dungeon.
Eh...
Thanks a lot.
[Buzzing]
Yes, Eddie?
Phase two completed.
Over and out.
Good boy.
[Chuckling]
Now they're sitting close together
with the lights down low.
All we need is some soft music.
Leave it to me.
Shades ofTristan and Isolde,
shoot me a love theme
straight from the shoulder.
?? [Organ: "Let Me Call You Sweetheart'"]
The organ, it's playing by itself!
Yes, isn't it romantic?
You hear that? It worked.
Oh, Grandpa, you are a genius!
Oh, I must admit that you...
?? [Glissando, Upbeat Melody]
What was that?
Something must have gone wrong.
What? It's never done that before!
Aunt Lily! Grandpa!
Help!
Grandpa.!
Grandpa! Herman! Come on!
Not me. You made your kettle of fish,
now sleep in it.
So there!
[Gasps]
Oh!
Down! Down, boy! Sit!
Stay! Down, boy!
Hold it, hold it.!
Down, down.!
Stop.!
[Overlapping Shouts]
- Alan! Alan!
- [Door Creaks, Shuts]
Whoa!
Herman, come quick!
We need your help!
Herman! Well, don't just stand there!
Do something!
Allow me.
?? [Slows, Stops]
There.
[Chuckles]
I hope it doesn't wriggle
till after sundown.
You want a little more coffee?
No, no. That's okay.
I've stopped shaking now.
What happened?
You told me this girl was such a doll.
Oh, Marilyn is.
But that house and the aunt
and the grandfather.
Boy, they're like something
out of Edgar Allan Poe.
Well, I guess you'll be
scratching her off your list, huh?
Gosh, no. I can't afford to,
not since I saw that
solid gold deposit they made.
Ben, that girl has really got what
it takes... a hundred and eighty
thousand dollars'worth.
I wouldn't mind saying "I do"
to a balance like that, huh?
You know something, Alan?
You're really a rat.
Okay, okay. But you'll talk
nicer to me when I'm a rich rat.
Herman, frankfurters, please.
If you'll just wait, Grandpa,
they'll be there in a minute.
Hey, how come Marilyn's not
eating with us again tonight?
Because, Eddie, that nice young boy
from the bank called her...
and asked her out on another date.
[Laughs]
That's four dates this week,
and he's always so anxious
to be alone with her.
When she comes to the door,
he won't even come into the house.
He just rushes her into the car
and takes off!
What kept you?
You know, this is the first young man
that's really seemed interested in Marilyn.
[Gasps]
Wouldn't it be wonderful
if he asked her to marry him?
I'm all for it, all for it.
I haven't been to a wedding
since I married my 140th wife.
I hope Marilyn has as wonderful
a wedding as we had, Herman.
It was so touching when
that mad scientist gave you away...
and then presented me
with a copy of your blueprints.
I know, dear.
I just hope wherever Marilyn is tonight,
she's looking into a pair of eyes
as romantic as mine.
[Laughs]
There.
Does that change your mind any?
Gosh, Alan, I don't know.
An elopement sounds romantic
and all that, but I hate to do things
behind my family's back.
Now, wait a minute. You say they
love you and want you to be happy.
They'll get used to it.
But I think you better talk
to my uncle about something
as important as marriage.
He likes to do things
the old-fashioned way.
It's just the way he's put together.
But that's just it.
What if he says no or tells us to wait?
We might even lose each other forever.
You wouldn't want that to happen,
would you, doll?
Well, Alan, l...
Now, what were you saying?
Well,
an elopement might not
be such a bad idea after all.
Arrive New York Harbor, Friday.
Will see you on weekend.
Hope money is in safe place.
Love and kisses, Uncle Gilbert.
Thank you, Operator.
Ho-ho!
Oh, Grandpa, isn't that exciting?
Yes.
He'll be here for the weekend.
Oh-ho-ho! Good old Gilly!
He always was a fun fellow.
Now he'll get to meet
Marilyn's beau,
and if there's a wedding in the family,
he can stay over for it.
Yes, and if Marilyn gets to marry
that Mr. Benson, I won't mind
having a banker in the family.
After all, a fella who works in a vault
can't be all bad.
Well, maybe we're getting
our hopes too high.
After all, Marilyn is plain,
and, well...
[Phone Ringing]
I'll get it.
?? [Humming]
Yeah, hello. It's the Munster residence.
The Count speaking.
You don't know me, sir,
but I'm a friend of Alan Benson's.
I thought I should warn you about
something that's going to happen tonight.
What? Elopement?
Yes, sir, and I feel
it's my duty to tell you.
He's marrying your niece for one reason...
that money you have in our bank.
Hello? Hello?
Hello!
Grandpa!
What-What's this
about an elopement?
[Groans]
That fella's marrying Marilyn for her money.
And they're gonna elope tonight!
Now let me get this straight.
This fellow, Benson, is eloping
with our niece, Marilyn, tonight...
in order to get that hundred and eighty
thousand dollars we put in the bank?
- Yes, Herman, and Grandpa
and I have worked out a plan.
- I'm all ears.
Well, first of all,
Marilyn is so infatuated with this boy,
that if we told her the truth,
she wouldn't believe it, right?
Right.
Now, the next step is to get
Marilyn out of the way tonight,
so she can't elope with him, right?
Right.
And then we can confront this boy
with what we know. You follow me?
Follow you?
If we were any closer, we'd be dancing.
But how do we get
Marilyn out of the way?
Grandpa has a magic spell that'll transport her
back to Transylvania for the night.
And then, right after we get rid of
this Benson bum, I bring Marilyn back.
[Chuckles]
I got this spell right out of my magic book.
Herman, it's our only chance.
That mean Mr. Benson is going to be
here at midnight to elope with Marilyn.
Come on. Let's go upstairs
and get this over with.
Sure are a lot of mean people
in the world.
Why can't life be the way it is
in Mary Poppins?
Aah!
[Groans]
Meanie!
Marilyn... [Chuckles]
Come with me...
and stay right over here.
Eddie, over there, Lily, right here...
and Herman,
I'd like to have you over here.
Grandpa, what is this all about?
Marilyn, we'll explain later.
It's for your own good.
Eh, Marilyn dear, be a good girl,
and humor your poor,
old, decrepit grandfather.
Thank you.
Don't let time or space detain ya.
Here you go to Transylvania.
Grandpa!
L-It worked!
That was really neat!
[Chuckles]
Grandpa, you really... Eh, Grandpa?
Grandpa! Lily, where did Grandpa go?
Eh, Lily? Lily? Lily!
Eh, Eddie, where-where's Lily?
Eddie? Eddie?
Where is everybody?
Hmm. [Clicks Tongue]
Well, wouldn't you know?
That old goofball "overspelled" himself!
They've all been transported!
[Phone Ringing]
Every time there's a crisis,
some boob has to telephone.
[Ringing Continues]
Huh!
Hello?
Oh, hello, Grandpa.
Where are you?
Where am I?
I'm in the Happy Valley Motel in Kansas City.
Oh, really?
Say, how is the weather there?
Oh, it is clearing up a bit...
[Groans] Herman, the spell backfired.
We're all here.
I'll be darned.
When are you coming back?
Look, Herman, all I've got
with me is the one-way spell.
You've gotta go down to the dungeon...
and get the return-trip spell out of
my magic book and read it to me
over the phone.
Gotcha. Uh, be right back.
- Uh, Grandpa.
- Yes, Herman?
- Um, what was it I was supposed to get?
- The return-trip spell out of my magic book.
That's right. Uh, don't go away.
- Eh, Grandpa, it's me.
- Herman, did you get the formula?
No. It was dark down there,
and the book snapped at me again.
Oh, brother!
Will someone please tell me
what's going on here?
Yeah, Mom. What's up?
Oh, Grandpa, give me that phone.
Take Marilyn in the other room
and tell her what happened.
Some sorcerer's apprentice he is.
Well, come, my dear.
I'll break it to you gently.
Now, first of all, that fella
you're in love with is a rat fink.
- Herman, are you there?
- Yes, Lily.
Now, listen, Herman.
It's almost midnight.
That Alan Benson is going to show up
in 20 minutes to elope with Marilyn.
When he does, you're just going to have
to be there waiting for him in her place.
Well, that's a good idea, dear,
but don't you think he'll notice the difference?
Oh, Herman!
Herman, I don't want you to elope with him.
I just want you to tell him off.
I see, dear. Tell him off. Uh, right.
Be forceful. Right.
Don't worry.
I'll give him a piece of my mind.
When I have to be,
I can be a pretty terrifying individual.
[Wind Gusting]
Hmm. He'll be here in ten minutes.
[Clicks Tongue]
I guess I'll just turn out the light,
so I don't have to look at this
horrible furniture of Marilyn's.
Boy, when he comes through
that window and finds me sitting here,
he's really gonna think he tangled with a tiger.
[Chuckles]
[Yawning]
[Snoring]
[Snoring Continues]
[Whispering]
Marilyn!
It's me, honey.
I've come to get ya!
How could she sleep at a time like this?
The least she could do is knock it off
with the snoring.
Come on, sweetheart. Wake up!
It's your Prince Charming
who's come to take you away.
Sweetie, darling. It's me, honey.
That's strange.
She must wear mittens to bed.
Darling, are you...
Ohh! Ohh!
Uh, young man, wait! Young man!
Young man?
Uh, young man!
Young man? Young man.!
Young man! L...
Well, he certainly left in a hurry.
I didn't even have a chance to tell him off.
Well, I guess everyone looks
kind of frightening when they first wake up.
Well, Herman, I must say,
it's nice to be back home...
after a certain party
forced us to take a plane
all the way back from Kansas City.
I'm sorry, Lily.
But I at least saved you a full fare...
by flying back under my own power!
And I'm glad to be home too.
The truth about Alan was an awful shock,
but I guess I'll get used to it.
I'm sure you will, dear.
And to think that the money that
that young man was after isn't ours at all.
It belongs to Uncle Gilbert. Hmm!
Hey, Uncle Gilbert
oughta be here any minute.
Huh?
His plane got into the airport
15 minutes ago.
Oh!
Dear, I hope he doesn't have
a hard time getting a taxi.
You know, sometimes...
[Pounding]
I'll bet that's Uncle Gilbert!
I'll get it!
That's who it is!
Herman!
Uncle Gilbert! Come right in!
How are you?
Well, now, it certainly is good...
to drop in on my favorite relatives!
Oh, yes!
Hello, Uncle Gilbert!
Hi, Uncle Gilbert!
[Overlapping Chatter]
Come right in and sit down,
Uncle Gilbert!
We haven't seen you
in such a long time.
Come right in and sit down.
How are things going?
Swimmingly.
Oh, but say, let me get out of these
dry things and into something wet.
Well, sit down, Uncle Gilbert!
Yes!
Well, Uncle Gilbert, before I forget it,
all that money you sent us is safe in the bank.
Fine, fine.
But, Uncle Gilbert? Uh, just one thing.
Uh, we were a little curious.
Where did you get all that gold?
Yeah, Uncle Gilbert.
Where'd you get all those neat
Spanish doubloons and rare gold pieces?
Oh, those! Oh, why, Eddie, my boy,
that's loose change I picked up...
in ships and treasure chests
lying around in my neighborhood.
- No foolin'!
- Sure!
That's one reason I wouldn't live
anyplace else in the world.
Oh, there's a lot of advantages, my boy,
to being the Creature
from the Black Lagoon.
[Eddie]
Yeah!
[All Laughing]