[Sighs]
Hi, Grandpa. Where's Lily?
She's gone to bed.
You better go up
and tell her where you've been.
You've been out
three nights in a row.
What are you up to?
Grandpa, I don't want
Lily to know,
but I'm engaged in a project
that is going to benefit mankind...
and keep the streets
of our country safe...
for women
and children everywhere.
No.
Yes.
I'm a detective.
What? You, a detective?
Herman. Herman,
do me a favor.
Hmm?
When the boys
from the happy hatch come...
to fit you with that
canvas housecoat,
please, don't tell 'em
you're my son-in-law!
[Laughing]
What time did Uncle Herman
get home last night, Aunt Lily?
Not till 11:00.
He had some vague excuse
about getting lost
on the way home from work.
- Hey, maybe Pop is leadin' a double life.
- A double life?
Yeah. He's really
a criminal on parole,
and he has to go out at night
and pay blackmail to some crooks,
so they won't tell everybody
his mother runs a saloon
in New Orleans.
Eddie Munster, wherever
do you get such ideas?
It was on the second feature
at the kiddies' matinee.
Oh, those horror shows!
Eddie, you should spend
Saturday afternoons at home...
doing something
more wholesome,
like digging up bones
in the backyard with Spot.
Where's Uncle Herman now,
Aunt Lily?
He's down in that lab again
with Grandpa.
I don't know what they're up to.
It's awfully quiet down there.
I'd feel a lot better if I could
hear a few explosions.
"Follow that man.
"Learn to be a detective
in your spare time.
"Earn up to $75 a week.
"Glamour, excitement...
Official badge with first lesson."
[Chuckles]
"United States National Federal
Detective Academy.
Box 14, Tijuana, Mexico."
[Snickers]
Oh, boy.
My son-in-law,
the wetback detective.
Herman, this is a gyp outfit.
Oh, no, they're not.
[Chuckles]
That's where
I have you, Grandpa.
They sent me
this official detective kit.
See? Here's my
fingerprinting equipment.
- [Grunts]
- [Laughs]
And these are what is
commonly known in the trade...
as restraining cuffs.
[Clatters]
Well... Oh, it doesn't matter anyway.
They didn't send me the key.
And, eh-eh, what is this,
a Tijuana phone book?
No. This is
my 20 easy lessons.
See? Here's a chapter
on how to follow men.
Eh?
Here's a chapter
on how to follow women.
Here's a chapter on how to follow men
disguised as women.
You see, Grandpa?
I am too a detective.
Okay. Okay.
Good. Good.
[Chuckles]
You're a detective.
What do you do now?
What do I do now?
I give up my present
low-salary job...
for the high-paying rewards...
of a career in law enforcement.
You mean quit your job
down at the parlor?
Herman, you're a big man
down there.
You, who started out
12 years ago as a nail boy.
I'm not quitting
right now, Grandpa.
I need more experience.
That's why I've been out
the last three nights...
practicing how
to shadow people.
Grandpa? Grandpa...
Oh!
Herman, hmm?
Not only will you
get Lily mad,
but if you
keep shadowing people,
you will wind up
with what is known
in the trade...
as a belt in the mouth!
Grandpa, you can laugh
if you want to,
but I'm on the verge
of a career in law enforcement.
I've already sent in my application
to the Kempner Detective Agency
right here in this town.
They said they'd call me.
Are you sure about that?
That's just what they said:
"Don't call us, we'll call you."
Herman?
And just where do you think
you're going again tonight?
Uh... Eh, just out, dear.
There's some secret work
I have to do...
that will eventually be
of great benefit to my family.
All right, go ahead.
I don't suppose it matters to you
that you're completely ruining
my plans for the evening.
Oh? What plans
are those, dear?
Oh, just that I'm supposed
to go out tonight...
and collect for our favorite charity,
Bundles for Transylvania.
I thought that my husband
could at least be with me...
when I knock on strange doors.
But that's all right.
Go ahead, stay out all evening
with your "secret" work.
- But, Lily!
- Oh, no.
Go on. And while you're out,
why don't you send
a one-word telegram...
to our poor friends
in the Old Country...
"Starve!"
But...
[Groans]
[Gasps]
Oh, it's only you.
Well, w-why don't you
sit closer?
What for?
So I can give you a kiss.
Oh, l-I'd be embarrassed.
Well, then close your eyes.
Will you close yours?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
One, two, three.
[Speaking With Chinese Accent]
Oh, um, me no Peeping Tom.
Me number-one detective.
Oh!
Well, he's not at the office.
[Scoffs]
Secret work, my foot.
I'll just bet he's seeing
another woman.
Oh, Aunt Lily.
I'm going down
first thing in the morning...
to the Kempner Detective Agency
and have your Uncle Herman followed!
[Door Creaking]
Well, what do you suppose
he's been doing, Aunt Lily?
Well, I don't know.
But the next time he does it,
there'll be a detective
behind him taking notes!
Well, I'm sure we can
handle this case, Mrs. Munster.
Would you give us
a description of your husband?
Well, he's average height,
about 7 foot 3.
Seven foot 3?
[Chuckles]
Did he ever
play basketball?
No. J- Just in the backyard
with our son, Eddie.
But he had to give it up.
He kept catching his head
in the hoop.
- How about his weight?
- Three spins.
Three spins?
Yes. When he gets
on the bathroom scale...
you know the little dial...
well, it spins around three times.
Put down "heavy."
How does he wear his hair?
Well, um, he wears it
a little long on the sides...
and, uh, flat on top.
- Ears?
- Mm-hmm, two.
Oh, they're not a matched set,
but only the family can tell.
Herman has a very
distinguished lantern jaw...
and piercing eyes.
And, um, a classic nose.
Oh, and an overhanging forehead.
Overhanging forehead?
Yes. It keeps the water
out of his eyes
when he's in the shower.
Any, uh, scars or birthmarks?
No. Oh.
He does have
a cute little dimple...
right here.
- Dimple?
- It's about five inches long,
and this wide and all "jaggedy."
Do you suppose you could
have him followed
and find out what he's up to?
Well, uh, I tell you, Mrs. Munster,
we're pretty busy right now.
We got a lot of husbands to follow.
It always happens when
the warm weather sets in.
Uh, suppose I talk this over
with my partner,
and we'll get right back to you.
Well, l-I certainly hope
you don't find out
it's another woman.
I'd hate to lose Herman.
He's one in a million.
One in a million?
From the description,
I'd say the odds are
a lot higher than that.
Mike, I'd hate to put
one of our men on this case.
The whole thing
sounds so weird.
There's no telling
what might happen.
Yeah, but...
[Phone Ringing]
Kempner Detective Agency.
This is 702 speaking.
I mailed an application
and called you several times
last week.
It's that crank
who calls himself 702
calling back.
You know,
that boob who wants
to be a detective?
Shall I tell him
to get lost again?
Wait a minute.
We got nothing to lose.
Why don't we put him
on this case, have him follow
this Munster character?
If he gets his head bashed in,
at least the union won't be
on our necks.
Uh, look, uh, 702,
we got a case for you.
Ajealous woman wants
her husband followed.
We'll send you the details.
You take it from there.
Oh, golly. Oh, gee.
But don't send it to my house.
Uh, send it to my place of business.
Oh, and use my code name.
I don't want anyone to know
what I'm up to.
Good-bye.
Oh, boy! Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
[Laughing]
I'm a detective!
Now, Grandpa,
the agency sent me
this description of the man
I'm supposed to follow.
Evidently he goes out
late at night without
any explanation,
and his wife is suspicious.
This man is a philanderer.
Herman, this man is a bum!
That's what he is!
Be that as it may.
According to lesson 12
of the correspondence course,
the first thing to do
is make a composite drawing
of the suspect.
I suppose
you could do that.
Fine.
Now, you read the description
while I make the drawing,
like the shrewd,
well-trained detective I am.
Good.
[Groans]
What's the matter?
Somebody stole my crayon!
Will you calm down?
Here. Here's a pencil.
Oh, thank you, Grandpa.
What's the matter now?
There's no point on it.
Give me that.
[Grinding]
Thank you.
Now, you read the description
of the man I'm supposed to follow...
while I make the sketch.
Good.
Now,
"Height: 7 foot 3."
My, he's a big one.
"Weight: Heavyset.
"Hair: Long on the sides,
very flat on top."
Long on sides,
flat on top.
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
"Ears: Do not match."
"Ears do not match."
What are you
looking at now?
Nothing.
"Lantern jaw."
"Piercing eyes."
"Classic nose."
Lantern jaw, piercing eyes,
classic nose.
Ist das nicht ein classic nose?
Ja, das ist ein classic nose.
Flat on top, lantern jaw,
long on sides,
piercing eyes, classic nose.
Oh, du schöne, oh, du schöne,
oh, du schöne classic nose.
Herman, will you knock it off?
I'm sorry, Grandpa.
I guess I just got carried away.
After all,
I was made in Germany.
[Chuckling]
"Protruding brows."
What are you looking at now?
Nothing.
"Jagged dimple on forehead."
Gotcha. Well, Grandpa?
Here's what the poor boob looks like.
What's the matter?
Herman, I've got news for you.
This poor boob... is you!
Me? No.
No, i-i-it couldn't be me.
Grandpa, this man
is a philanderer.
If I were chasing women,
I'd be the first one to know it.
Wait a minute, Herman.
I've got the answer
to the whole thing.
Look, it says here...
that the woman who wants
this man followed...
is Mrs. Lily Munster.
But why would Lily
want me followed?
Because you've been
going out at night.
She hired the detective agency
to find out what you've been up to.
Oh, I get it.
Then the man
I'm supposed to follow
is Herman Munster.
Right.
Herman, may I ask
what you're doing?
Th-There must be a chapter
on how to follow yourself.
Herman, look,
you can't tell Lily
you're a detective.
But I have a scheme.
Now, you go out tonight...
and stay out as late as usual.
Then, then as Agent 702,
you file a very favorable report
on Herman Munster.
The agency gives
this report to Lily.
Lily is happy, you're happy,
and the agency is happy!
Marilyn, I want you
to sit over there on the sofa.
Grandpa, in your chair.
And Herman,
I want you to sit right here
so you'll be next to me.
Oh, why all
the formality, Aunt Lily?
It almost seems like
the reading of a will.
I'm afraid it's not
that happy an occasion.
- Then, uh, what is it, Lily?
- I've brought you all together...
because a certain member
of our family...
has indulged in many
unexplained absences
in the evenings.
Now, rather than accuse
this person unjustly,
I have had
this woman chaser followed.
How do you like that, Grandpa?
My own wife, Lily,
has had me followed.
I can't believe it.
Now, what kind of creatures
are we turning into?
Anyway, I got this report...
from the detective agency
this morning.
And I'm going to
read it right now...
in front of all of you.
Go right ahead, Lily.
I'm ready for the worst.
"Report submitted by Agent 702
on Herman Munster.
"8:17, suspect left house.
"8:20, suspect patted
stray dog on head.
"Proceeded to Maple Avenue.
Helped old lady across street.
"9:06, attended church.
"9:38, prevented man
from beating horse.
9:41, attended church."
Well, so far, it sounds like
an evening with Pat Boone.
"10:03, followed suspect
to Gaiety Burlesque Theater."
Oh, Uncle Herman!
"10:04, suspect crossed street
to avoid Gaiety Burlesque Theater.
10:15, suspect entered
Rudy's Bar and Grill."
Aha! "10:16, suspect
showed picture...
"of wife and child to Rudy.
Refused free beer. '"
I always carry that picture.
[Snorts]
"10:30, visited park.
Fed starving pigeons.
"Bought matches
from little match girl.
"Attended church.
Came home.
"Found wife asleep.
"Kissed wife good night.
Went to bed. '"
Herman, I'm so sorry.
L-I never should have
blamed you...
for doing anything wrong,
pussycat.
L-I'll never
mistrust you again...
in all my lives.
There, there, Lily.
Uh, I forgive you, dear.
Uh, but I always want you
to remember this...
I want you to remember
one thing.
In the great vegetable market
of life,
I have never been one
to pinch the tomatoes.
- Herman!
- [Gasps]
You're not going out
again tonight.
You want to get
in trouble again?
No, Grandpa.
It's just that I did
such a good job as Agent 702,
the Kempner Agency called me up
and gave me another case.
I'm gonna be a bodyguard.
There's some poor unfortunate woman
whose husband has been threatening her.
And my orders are,
if he comes around,
not to get violent,
just scare him away.
[Laughing]
You?
How could you scare anybody?
[Honks]
It's nice of you to help me
with my charity drive tonight, Marilyn.
With all these problems,
I've been neglecting
my house-to-house calls.
Well, Bundles for Transylvania
is a worthy cause.
Why, back in the Old Country
they should get down
on all fours...
and thank you
for what you've done.
Come on, dear.
Let's go.
I, um, l-I just wanted
to thank you, Mr. Kempner,
for sending over a bodyguard
wearing such a frightening disguise.
Yes. Yes, I'm sure
he'll scare my husband away
if he comes around.
[Gasps]
Oh, and, um,
I want to apologize for fainting
when Agent 702 showed up.
Yes. For a minute
I thought he really
looked like that.
Yes. Well, thank you again,
Mr. Kempner.
Good-bye.
You're sure I can't get you
some coffee or something?
Oh, no, thank you.
I'm-I'm very comfy.
[Doorbell Rings]
Don't worry.
I'll get it.
[Doorbell Rings]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Good evening.
I'm collecting for...
Herman!
What are you doing here?
Oh, Lily.
W-Well, you see, l...
[Woman]
If that's my husband, get rid ofhim.
Uncle Herman!
Eh... Lily,
you may not believe this,
but I'm Secret Agent 702.
Herman, you may not
believe this,
but I'm Sonny Liston!
Come on, Marilyn.
And when
the Kempner Detective Agency...
gave me the job
of being bodyguard
to Mrs. Andrews,
I was on my way
to fame and fortune
as a detective.
Tsk. But tonight
when you knocked me out,
they fired me.
There, there.
L-I'm sorry, dear.
I had no idea you were
trying so hard to make good
for Eddie and me.
Come on, Marilyn.
Let's go in the kitchen...
and fix sweetie
a glass of warm milk.
[Laughing]
Boy, Herman,
you sure got yourself
into a mess this time.
Don't worry, Grandpa.
I'll never try to be
a detective again.
Good.
But you know
something, Grandpa,
I saw this ad in a magazine
at Mrs. Andrews's house...
for something
where I can't fail.
What ad?
See?
I'm gonna study hairdressing
in my spare time...
and make a fortune
with my own beauty parlor.