Grandpa, this isn't
going to hurt, is it?
I told you, Herman...
I've done it a hundred times to you
before and it never bothered you.
You're just nervous 'cause
I ran out of anesthetic.
[snickering]
I guess if it's got to come
off, it's got to come off.
I'll just there take a little
off the top and trim the sides.
[creaking]
[gun clicking]
Hey, P0P!
[grunts]
Eddie, don't you ever
do that, Son...
when Grandpa is giving me
a haircut.
He might snip my bangs and
spoil my Steve McQueen image.
I'm sorry, Pop.
I just want to show you
this pamphlet.
The whole town is having
Frontier Days this weekend.
Yes, I read about that
in the newspaper.
They're having a parade,
rodeo and contests.
And all the people are dressing
themselves up as pioneers and cowboys.
It's all set, Pop.
I entered your name
in the bucking bronco contest.
Bucking bronco contest?
Sure.
I'm gonna be
so proud of you, Pop.
I've been telling all the guys
around the rodeo...
that you're the greatest rider
in the world.
Well, shuckies.
That was
right smart of you, partner.
[laughing]
Grandpa.
[grunts]
Hank, it looks like...
we've got some pretty safe entries
in the bronco busting event.
They're all amateurs.
But I am a little concerned about
this fella, Herman Munster.
Yeah.
He's the guy whose kid was here bragging
about what a great rider his pop is.
That's right.
And we can't take any chances
of anybody...
walking off with that $500
prize money we're offering.
So just to be
on the safe side...
let's put this Munster
character on Volcano.
Volcano? That's not a
horse, it's a time bomb.
He'll wreck this guy Munster.
So what? If anything
should go wrong...
we'll return his entry fee
to his widow.
Herman...
you on a bucking bronco?
Why, you couldn't even ride
a kiddie car.
Yes, I could.
I used to ride Eddie's
all the time.
But, Uncle Herman,
riding a bucking bronco...
is one of the most dangerous
sports in the whole world.
You might get killed.
Herman, it'd be just like you to pull a
dirty trick like that on me, you bum.
You don't even have enough life
insurance to keep me in cigars.
Golly, when Eddie first mentioned
the idea of bronco busting to me...
it sounded kind of like
a fun thing.
But, dear, the last time you were
on a merry-go-round horse...
you had to wear
a safety belt.
I don't want you to go through with this.
You'll just go out and get yourself killed.
You're only 152 years old.
And I won't have you cut down
in the prime of life.
Gee, dear, I promised Eddie.
He's counting on me.
What can I say to him?
It's simple.
You just go up
to your son...
and tell him that his daddy
is a no-good, rotten coward.
I can't do that.
Boys don't have many heroes left
that they can look up to these days.
If I let him down, all he has
left is Smokey the Bear.
Herman, why don't you use
child psychology?
All you have to do is talk
to Eddie in such a way...
that he'll be the one who suggests
that you drop out of the rodeo.
That's a good idea.
That's just what I'll do.
But instead of being blunt and
direct, I'll be subtle...
and talk to Eddie
on his own mental level.
Yeah. And if you can't quite get
up to it, do the best you can.
[laughing]
[snarling]
And once upon a time,
in this big, big castle...
there lived this
very brave knight...
named Sir Herman the Great.
Gee, Pop, he had
the same name as you.
Well, well,
what do you know about that?
Anyway, in a nearby cave...
there lived this very mean,
mean dragon.
What did he do
that was so bad?
Well, he went around
abducting young maidens...
and pillaging the countryside
and terrorizing villages...
and doing
other naughty things.
And everyone said that Sir Herman
the Great was the only one...
that was brave enough and strong
enough to vanquish the dragon.
There's a white knight
on television like that.
Except, all he ever does is
chase dirt out of blue jeans.
Anyway, as Sir Herman the Great
was starting out on his way...
to vanquish the dragon, his
wife and his father-in-law...
and his niece
came running out and cried:
"O brave Sir Herman, prithee
do not go forth this day...
for the dragon
might slay thee."
Boy, they sure talked corny
in those days.
Well, anyway...
although Sir Herman was on his
way to slay the cruel dragon...
he thought it over
and realized...
that he could be eaten up
by the dragon.
And if the dragon
ate him up...
then there would be
no one left...
to take care of his little
home and his little family.
Now, what do you think
about that?
I think the knight was a rotten,
chicken, yellow coward.
Oh.
You do, huh?
Yeah.
I think you ought to sue the
guy who made up that story...
for calling the knight
by your name.
For you'd never chicken out like that.
Would you, Pop?
Gadzooks, no.
I bet tomorrow you'll be the
bravest guy in the whole rodeo.
Yeah, sure.
Well, good night, Son.
Goodnight, Pop.
[door creaking open]
If I had my way, I'd just as soon
chase dirt out of blue jeans.
[Volcano snorting]
[Volcano whinnying]
Hey, get a load of Volcano.
He's sure calmed down
since yesterday.
[neighing continues]
(Hank)
You still think...
we ought to put this
Munster guy in that horse?
Sure, why not?
But tell
the ambulance attendants...
that the minute he hits the ground,
to throw a sheet over him quick.
We don't want his broken bones
to dampen the festivities.
[crashing]
£J“[humming]
Spot.
[growling]
[grunting]
Spot, get out in the yard.
I don't want you in the
kitchen, always underfoot.
Now scat.
[groaning]
Sorry, Spot.
Aunt Lily...
is Uncle Herman going to ride
that bronco in the rodeo today?
Yes, Marilyn.
I did everything I could
to talk him out of it.
But he said
a knight should be proud...
to ride forth
and slay dragons for his son.
I guess he's been reading
Prince Valiant again.
Where's Uncle Herman now?
Down in the dungeon.
He is so nervous and so tense.
He asked Grandpa to do
something to relax his nerves.
That is a good idea.
I just hope
he doesn't overdo it.
The last time
Grandpa relaxed him...
his nerves were so loose...
that we had to call in a piano
tuner to tighten them up.
Grandpa, have you found
anything yet to make me brave?
When I think of riding a
bucking bronco, I'm petrified.
What are you knocking? Some of
my best friends are petrified.
No, I mean scared.
Haven't you got
any brave pills I can take?
Well...
I made these in the Middle Ages
for Richard the Lion-Hearted.
Did they work?
I'll have you know that before he took
these, he was known as Chicken Dickie.
Shall I take some of these?
No.
It says they're good only if
you're going on a crusade...
and I don't think you wanna take
that much time off from work.
Grandpa, you gotta give me
something to make me a hero.
I got to ride that horse in an hour.
Herman, let's face it.
A nice, handsome,
pleasant man you are...
but with all the pills in the
world, a hero you ain't.
What am I going to do?
[snaps fingers]
It just came to me. Herman...
now, supposing the horse you rode
today was gentle and kind...
and you and he had sort of...
an under-the-table deal.
That's fine, but I'm not very
proficient at talking to horses.
You're very proficient
at talking to me, aren't you?
Yeah. Supposing I turn
myself into a horse.
You mean you would be the bucking
bronco I'd ride at the rodeo?
Grandpa, that's a wizard idea.
"Astronauts...
"avocados...
"aborigines...
animals."
No.
What's the matter?
This animal bottle is so old,
the label has fallen off.
Well, I'll just have to
take my chances...
and hope I come up
with a horse.
Mom, where's Pop?
It's time to leave for the rodeo
and we don't wanna be late.
He's still down
in the dungeon with Grandpa.
I hope they're not making up another
batch of Dad's old-fashioned plasma.
Now, Eddie, don't get impatient.
I'm sure--
[goat bleating]
Aunt Lily, I could have
sworn I heard a goat.
So did I.
We're getting so nervous that
we're starting to hear things.
Grandpa.
You must've taken the wrong pill.
You're not a horse, you're a goat.
I can tell because
horses don't have horns.
Don't just sit there, Herman.
Give me another pill.
Yeah.
[Grandpa bleating]
Here, try this one.
[gulps]
[squealing]
Well, Grandpa, that's no good. I
can't ride a skunk in a rodeo.
Shut up and try another pill
before I let you have it.
Listen.
[Pig grunting]
Now I can swear
I hear a pig grunting.
A pig?
You don't suppose they're having a
barbecue at a time like this, do you?
Grandpa. Herman.
You'll be late for the rodeo.
(Herman)
We'll be right with you, Lily.
Grandpa, now look
what you've done.
You've gone and made
a pig of yourself.
Another pill.
[neighing]
[laughing]
Grandpa, you're beautiful.
Iask you...
is this a horse,
or is this a horse?
Grandpa.
[coughing]
Howdy, folks?
I'm all ready for the rodeo.
Gee, Pop, you look neat.
Just like the cowboys
in that cigarette commercial.
Thank you, Son.
Herman, please call this off.
If you get up
on a bucking bronco...
you'll just make a fool of
yourself and probably get killed.
You don't know anything
about being a cowboy.
Shucks.
What you talking about, ma'am?
I'm a rooting, tooting...
fancy booting,
two-gun shooting...
pistol-packing poppa
from Possum Prairie.
[laughing]
Dear, will you help me?
Marilyn.
Eddie, can you help your father pry
himself loose from his drawers?
Thank you.
I guess John Wayne and those
other fellows must...
grease their thumbs
before they try that.
I guess if we're going,
we better get started.
Where's Grandpa?
Grandpa just had a few things
he wanted to take care of...
and he'll meet us
at the rodeo.
You think you'll have any trouble
with that wild mustang, Pop?
I don't think so, Son.
I'm gonna handle that critter like
he was a member of my own family.
[snorting]
It certainly was nice of Uncle
Herman to get us this private box.
Well, we Munsters always
feel more at home in a box.
Boy, look at that guy.
Boy, that bull
really flipped him.
You poor man.
[screaming]
They really put on
a good show here, don't they?
Yes, I've never seen
that trick before.
Gee, I wonder where Pop is. The
bronco busting comes up next.
Well, I hope it's the bronco that
gets busted and not your father.
[people whistling]
[people cheering]
[man whooping]
Everybody's checked in for the bronco
busting but that Munster character.
Maybe he heard he was riding
Volcano and pulled up stakes.
I wouldn't blame him.
Hi, there.
I'm Herman Munster...
Bronco Buster.
Hiya, Munster.
Will you look at that guy?
He's tall in the saddle
and he ain't even on a horse.
Get a load of that face.
He must've gone
through a buffalo stampede.
I didn't think there were that
many buffalo left in America.
Excuse me, but I was wondering
if you could tell me...
what chute
I'm supposed to come out of?
Come out of Chute 4.
Number 4.
Thank you very much.
I'll be ready and waiting.
We better not put Volcano in that
chute until the last minute.
If Munster gets a look at that local mustang,
he'll know we pulled a ringer on him.
Grandpa?
[snorting]
Hey, Grandpa,
where are you?
Grandpa, it's me.
[snuffling]
Sorry, I thought
you were my grandfather.
(Grandpa)
Over here, Herman.
There you are.
Oh, my-
What a beautiful saddle
you're wearing.
Never mind, Herman.
What's the scoop?
I'll be coming out of Chute Number 4.
Now, make sure and be there.
Got you.
Get away from me, girlie.
I'm old enough
to be your father.
(announcer) Yes, siree. Look at that boy go.
Here we go now!
Stay right in there, boy.
[crowd roaring]
And now for
the bucking bronco contest.
The first rider
to go 10 seconds...
gets a $500 prize.
Mom, this is Pop's event.
Out of Chute Number 3,
it's Tex Rogers on Midnight.
[crowd cheering]
Here he comes, folks.
And there he goes.
[people clapping]
Oh, dear.
Eddie, you never should have
gotten your father into this.
This is worse than the time you talked
him into riding that surfboard...
and he knocked the end
off that new steel pier.
The time was
five and three-tenth seconds.
Now out of Chute 5, it's
Hugh Hobson on Nasty Nellie.
Ride it, cowboy, ride it.
[man whooping]
Where do you suppose
Grandpa is?
I don't know. He's never
around when you need him.
I suppose he's horsing
around someplace.
Hey, you stupid nag,
get out of here.
That's for Volcano. Get out.
Better get ready, Munster.
The way they're throwing them off,
you'll be up pretty soon now.
Yes, siree. I hope they give
me a horse with some spirit.
I'd hate to have to ride
some tired old grandfather.
[announcer chattering]
[audience clapping]
Hey, you.
Where do you think you're going?
Into Stall Number 4.
My son-in-law's gonna ride me
in the next event.
Come on, beat it, Pops.
Keep your hands off, buster. I'll
get you for cruelty to animals.
Hey, Charlie.
Got an old stew-bum here
that thinks he's a horse.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
[mumbling]
It wore off.
I'm not a horse anymore.
Of course
you're not a horse.
You're Snow White
and we're the Seven Dwarfs.
Get out of here
and don't come back.
[man whistling]
[men cheering]
[people clapping]
The time was
five and three-tenth seconds.
So far we have no winner.
Our final contestant,
coming out of Chute 4...
is Herman Munster on Volcano.
Oh, boy, that's Pop.
[people clapping]
I can't bear to look.
Volcano, nice Volcano.
Volcano, that was a neat name you
picked for yourself, Grandpa.
It makes you sound as though
you're gonna be rough.
Grandpa.
Grandpa, it's me, Herman.
I get it.
No conversation.
You wanna make it look good.
[whinnying]
Grandpa.
Grandpa, will you watch it?
You almost threw me off.
It's all right
to ham it up but--
[Volcano neighing]
Attaboy, Pop.
Stay with him,
Uncle Herman.
[Volcano neighing]
Hang on! Hang on!
Grandpa, will you watch it?
Grandpa.
I can't bear to look.
Grandpa, you big showoff.
Will you listen to me?
Ride him, Pop!
All right, Grandpa,
if you wanna play that way...
two can play that way
as well as one.
Uncle Herman is certainly showing
the spectators what he's made of.
Yes, and I hope
we can replace the parts.
[whistle blows]
[audience cheering]
The winner of the bucking bronco
contest is Herman Munster!
[people whistling]
[people cheering]
[people chattering]
[laughs]
Herman,
I'm so proud of you.
I'm just bat bumps all over.
Boy, Pop, you're the neatest
guy in the whole world.
Shucks, Eddie.
'Twern't nothing any other dad
wouldn't have done.
And now, ladies and gentlemen, it
becomes my great honor to present...
this beautiful trophy
and the $500...
to the winner of the bronco busting
contest, Mr. Herman Munster.
[audience cheering]
You know, your time was a new
world's record, Mr. Munster.
Before accepting this trophy, is
there anything you'd like to say?
Yes, I would. Thank you.
First of all,
it was quite a ride.
And I think that
under the circumstances...
some credit
should go to the horse.
Now, isn't that the gesture
of a truly great sportsman...
giving credit to the horse.
[laughing]
[people cheering]
[man whooping]
Take a bow, Grandpa.
Herman, we're all
so proud of you.
Come on, Grandpa, take a bow.
What are you waiting for?
Grandpa, where were you
when Uncle Herman was riding?
Yes, Grandpa.
Where were you when I was...
[nickering]
[exclaims]
What's going on, Grandpa?
Why did Herman faint?
Lily, I never thought I'd say
anything nice about my son-in-law...
but that big coward is the
greatest hero I ever saw.
Photographer, come
and take his picture anyway.
He looks more natural
that way.